<nodes>	
    <node>
		<Fname>
1calendar
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
2calendar
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
3give
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Philanthropy plays a crucial role in supporting the activities of the Division of Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine. The faculty provide the best possible care to our patients, conduct leading-edge research, and train the next generation of medical professionals. Your gift to the Division of Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine and the Department of Medicine will allow us to continue this commitment to excellence.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;How You Can Help&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://support.ucsf.edu/ucsf-foundation&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/make-a-gift.png&quot; class=&quot;imgRight&quot; style=&quot;border:none;&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;There are a variety of ways to support the Department of Medicine: pledges; outright gifts; planned giving options, including trusts and bequests; and endowed giving opportunities. You may direct your gift to a specific program or research area, or you can give to the Department of Medicine Opportunity Fund to support the most pressing needs of the Department. For further information about giving to the Department of Medicine, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.ucsf.edu/ways-to-give/ways-give-faq&quot;&gt;Support UCSF&lt;/a&gt; or  contact:&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Olivia Herbert&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			Tel: (415) 476-9878&lt;br&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:oherbert@support.ucsf.edu&quot;&gt;oherbert@support.ucsf.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
4hamilton
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/hamilton.jpg&quot; class=&quot;imgRight&quot;&gt;
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;The Division of Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine sponsors an annual named lectureship in honor of Dr. Alice Hamilton, the recognized founder of the modern discipline of Occupational Medicine in the US. The lecture occurs as a part of the Department of Medicine Medical Grand Rounds presentations, reaching a broad audience of internists, including physicians in training, many of whom are rarely otherwise exposed to this topic area.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Alice Hamilton Lecture for Thursday May 24, 2018:&lt;/h3&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Professor Rodney Ehrlich, School of Public Health and Family Medicine, University of Cape Town, South Africa -
			“Mineworkers’ Health in South Africa – the Perfect Storm of Dust, Tuberculosis and HIV”&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Past Alice Hamilton Lectures:&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017&lt;/b&gt; Marc Schenker (UC Davis) and Xóchitl Castañeda (UC Berkeley) -  The Occupational Health of Immigrant Workers: What an Internist Needs to Know &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016&lt;/b&gt; Paul Cullinan (Imperial College, London) - From Baker’s Asthma to Machinist’s Lung &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015&lt;/b&gt; Caroline Tanner and Samuel M. Goldman (UCSF) – Parkinsonism at Work and in the Environment&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014&lt;/b&gt; Jonathan Samet (USC) – The Risks of Breathing: Workplace &amp; Environmental Threats to Lung Health&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013&lt;/b&gt; Talmadge King (UCSF) – Hypersensitivity Pneumonitis:  A Paradigm of Occupational and Environmental Disease&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012&lt;/b&gt; Kjell Toren (Gothenburg, Sweden) – Pneumonia and Occupation: A New Paradigm for Investigating the Work-relatedness of Disease&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2011&lt;/b&gt; Kay Kreiss (NIOSH, West Virginia) – Investigating Emerging Work-Related Diseases&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2010&lt;/b&gt; Benoit Nemery (Leuven, Belgium) – Outbreaks of Occupational Disease: Form the Clinic to the Factory Floor and the Laboratory&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2009&lt;/b&gt; Josep Anto (Barcelona, Spain) – Unusual Environmental Disease Episodes: From Causation to Precaution&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2008&lt;/b&gt; David Schwartz (NIEHS, North Carolina) – Genes and the Environment: What’s in it for the Internist?&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2007&lt;/b&gt; David Christiani (Harvard) – Byssinosis in the 21st Century&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2006&lt;/b&gt; Brian Schwartz (Johns Hopkins) –  Chronic Occupational Disease: Evidence-Based Diagnosis&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2005&lt;/b&gt; Peter Spencer (University of Oregon) – Neurotoxins: New Approaches to Old Problems&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2004&lt;/b&gt; Gina Solomon (NRDC, San Francisco) – Why Should an Internist Care about Environmental Disease?&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2003&lt;/b&gt; Joel Kaufman (University of Washington) – Emerging Occupational and Environmental Disease&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2002&lt;/b&gt; Carrie Redlich (Yale University) – Why Internists Should Care about Occupational Disease&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2001&lt;/b&gt; No lecture &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2000&lt;/b&gt; Lee Newman (University of Colorado) – Occupational Causes of “Idiopathic” Conditions: Lessons for the Internist&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1999&lt;/b&gt; Patricia Buffler (UC Berkeley) – What Providers Need to Know about Occupational Health&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1998&lt;/b&gt; Howard Kipen (RWJ-Rutgers) – Gulf War and Related Health Syndromes: Unexplained Symptoms and Unknown Exposures&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1997&lt;/b&gt; Howard Hu (Harvard) – Lead Poisoning: A New Look at an Old Disease&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1996&lt;/b&gt; Susanna Von Essen  (University of Nebraska) – Overview of Farm Health and Safety&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1995&lt;/b&gt; Mark Cullen (Yale  University) – Occupational Medicine: Why It should Matter to an Internist&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1994&lt;/b&gt; Margot Becklake (McGill, Montreal) – Diseases of Life versus Diseases of Work&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1993&lt;/b&gt; Inaugural Alice Hamilton Lecture given by Philip Landrigan (Mt. Sinai, New York) &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
5history
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			
			&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/oem_history.jpg&quot; class=&quot;imgRight&quot;&gt;
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;The Division was founded in 1980 as part of the establishment of the multi-campus Northern California Center for Occupational and Environmental Health (UC Berkeley-UC Davis-UCSF), a unit that was mandated by the state legislature to provide training, research, and clinical service. &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;In 1992, Dr. Paul D. Blanc and Dr. John R. Balmes assumed the positions of Division Chiefs at Parnassus-Mt Zion and SFGH, respectively. In 2002, Dr. Balmes was additionally appointed to the faculty in the School of Public Health at UC Berkeley School of Public Health in its Division of Environmental Health Sciences and as Director of the multi-UC Campus Center for Occupational and Environmental Health (COEH). In January 2015, Dr. Blanc became Chief of an integrated three-campus Division of Occupational and Environmental Medicine that includes a new academic Division at the UCSF-affiliated San Francisco Veterans Affairs Medical Center (VAMC) as well as the existing Parnassus-Mt Zion and SFGH units. Dr. Balmes has assumed interim directorship of the joint UCSF-Berkeley Joint Medical Program in addition to his roles at SFGH, UC Berkeley, and COEH. Dr. Balmes also has a secondary appointment in the SFGH Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine; Dr. Blanc has a parallel secondary appointment in the Parnassus-Mt. Zion Pulmonary Division, as well as secondary appointments in the Department of Medical Anthropology, Social Medicine and Medical History and in the School of Pharmacy (through his work with the California Poison Control System San Francisco Division).&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;In addition to internationally recognized research programs in occupational and environmental lung diseases at both the Parnassus-Mt. Zion and SFGH campuses under the leadership of Drs. Blanc and Balmes, an internationally recognized program in ergonomics research that was established by Dr. David Rempel is based at the Richmond Field Station campus of UC Berkeley. The Division has long been the site of a CDC/National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH)-funded training program, the UCSF OEM Residency. This residency is an ACGME-accredited program that is governed by the American Board of Preventive Medicine. This training program has expanded further with additional extramural support from the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA). Division physicians provide clinical care at the UCSF Medical Center, SFGH, and the VAMC campuses, as well as medical direction for Occupational Health Services for employees at all three sites. Members of the Division faculty are prominent in a variety of scholarly endeavors. In 2014, long-time faculty member Dr. Robert Harrison co-edited the latest (5th) edition of Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine (Current Diagnosis and Treatment) with the Division’s Emeritus Professor Dr. Joseph LaDou. Faculty members also play leading roles in various public health policy activities at the state, national, and international levels.    
			
			 &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
6index
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/oemcollage2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ucsfoem&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&gt;
			
			&lt;br/&gt;
			&lt;br&gt;
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;The Division of Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine (OEM), separately constituted at the UCSF Parnassus, Mount Zion, San Francisco General Hospital , and  San Francisco Veterans Affairs  Medical Center campuses, is closely interlinked. It has achieved national and international recognition as a center for research, training, and clinical care in its field.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Moreover as one of the few such Divisions firmly based within a Department of Medicine (most academic units are housed in a Department of Preventive Medicine or a School of Public Health), UCSF’s occupational and environmental medicine presence is particularly noteworthy in US academic internal medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The mission of the Division of Occupational &amp;amp; Environmental Medicine at the University of California, San Francisco is to advance the field of occupational and environmental health through research, education, and service to patients and the community.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
7news
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
8news
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			&lt;h5&gt; Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine Newsletters &lt;/h5&gt;
			
			&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/newsletter_2012.pdf&quot;&gt;2012 Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/newsletter_2010.pdf&quot;&gt;2011 Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
			
			&lt;h5&gt;CME Archive&lt;/h5&gt;
			&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/2011.pdf&quot;&gt;2011 - Construction Industry: Old and Emerging Occupational Hazards&lt;/a&gt;
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/2010.pdf&quot;&gt;2010 - History of Occupational and Environmental Health&lt;/a&gt;
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/2009.pdf&quot;&gt;2009 - Health and Safety in Transportation Workers: Air, Sea, and Land&lt;/a&gt;
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/2008.pdf&quot;&gt;2008 - Occupational and Environmental Respiratory Disease &lt;/a&gt;
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/2006.pdf&quot;&gt;2006 - 
			Including a 12-hour Module on Pain Management&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
			
			
					</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
9personnel
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Experts that contribute to the Division’s success in the advancement of research, education, and services.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;table width=&quot;80%&quot; class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;
			
					&lt;a href=&quot;http://ergo.berkeley.edu/about/people.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Camilleri, Matt&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;		&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/ProfileDetails.aspx?From=SE&amp;Person=5247275&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Quinlan, Patricia J.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;		&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/ProfileDetails.aspx?From=SE&amp;Person=5306187&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Schick, Suzaynn F&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;		&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/ProfileDetails.aspx?From=SE&amp;Person=5481697&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wong, Hofer H.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;		&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
10staff
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			
			
			&lt;table&gt;
			&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td style=&quot;width:120px;&quot;&gt;Name&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Title&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Email&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Phone&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;/thead&gt;
			&lt;tbody&gt;
			
			
			&lt;tr &gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;Kimberly Cantero&lt;/td&gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;Director of Administration, SFGH, Parnassus, and VAMC &lt;/td&gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kimberly.cantero@ucsf.edu&quot;&gt;kimberly.cantero@ucsf.edu
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				    &lt;td style=&quot;width:18%;&quot;&gt;
			(415) 750-6901&lt;/td&gt;
			    &lt;/tr&gt;
			
			
			 &lt;tr class=&quot;even&quot;&gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;Alan Ong&lt;/td&gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;Research Administrator, Grants Management&lt;/td&gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:alan.ong@ucsf.edu&quot;&gt;alan.ong@ucsf.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;(415) 206-3106&lt;/td&gt;
				    &lt;/tr&gt;
			
			
			
			
			
			
			    &lt;tr&gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;Lucia Wang&lt;/td&gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;Residency Program Coordinator&lt;/td&gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:lucia.wang@ucsf.edu&quot;&gt;lucia.wang@ucsf.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
				    &lt;td&gt;(415) 221-4810 extension 26592&lt;/td&gt;
			    &lt;/tr&gt;
			
			
			
			
				    &lt;/table&gt;
			
			
			
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
11clinics
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			&lt;div style=&quot;float:right&quot;&gt;
			&lt;iframe width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:20px;&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=2330+Post+Street,+San+Francisco,+CA&amp;amp;aq=0&amp;amp;oq=2330+Post+Street,+San&amp;amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;amp;sspn=60.935792,61.787109&amp;amp;t=h&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=2330+Post+St,+San+Francisco,+California+94115&amp;amp;z=14&amp;amp;iwloc=A&amp;amp;output=embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
			 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Occupational and  Environmental Medicine Clinic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			2330 Post St., Suite 460&lt;br /&gt;
			San Francisco, CA 94117&lt;br /&gt;
			Phone:&amp;nbsp;(415) 885-7580&lt;br /&gt;
			Fax:&amp;nbsp;(415) 771-4472 &lt;br /&gt;
			Hours: Monday and Thursday&lt;br /&gt;
			9 a.m. – 4 p.m.&lt;br /&gt;
			 &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;If you're a UCSF Employee, please see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.occupationalhealthprogram.ucsf.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UCSF Occupational Health Program&lt;/a&gt; to make an appointment or find out more about our services.
			
			 
			&lt;p&gt;For all other referrals and appointments, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ucsfhealth.org/clinics/occupational_and_environmental_medicine/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UCSF Health Medical Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
12index
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/care.jpg&quot; class=&quot;imgRight&quot; alt=&quot;Clinic physician treating patient&quot;&gt;
			 &lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;The Occupational and Environmental Medicine Clinic at the UCSF Mount Zion campus provides specialty consultations for patients with illnesses, exposures, or health concerns related to their workplace, community, or home.&lt;/p&gt; 
			 
			&lt;p&gt;The clinic serves as a training site for OEM Residents and for Occupational Health Nursing and Industrial Hygiene students, for in-depth evaluations of exposure and disease. In addition to direct examination, the multidisciplinary clinic evaluation can include a review of the scientific literature, investigation of records, laboratory testing, and site visits to fully evaluate patients’ health issues.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
13about
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/nursing.jpg&quot; class=&quot;imgRight&quot;&gt;
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;The UCSF Occupational and Environmental Medicine (OEM) Training Program is designed to prepare physicians for occupational and environmental medicine practice and leadership roles including in clinical, academic, government, non-governmental organizations, consulting, or corporate settings. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The Program provides academic instruction, practicum experiences, and research opportunities. The large core and affiliated faculties based at the institution, together with extramural clinical faculty, and our faculty partners in nursing, industrial hygiene, and ergonomics provide this training. Graduates of the UCSF OEM Program are currently leaders in all of the practice settings listed above. Trainees will achieve competency in all core knowledge content areas in OEM, and are encouraged to develop areas of special expertise. In keeping with this goal, the educational program is individually tailored to meet the needs of each trainee. The UCSF OEM Program was founded in 1979, and is fully accredited by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acgme.org/acWebsite/home/home.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education (ACGME)&lt;/a&gt; for up to eight trainees. &lt;/p&gt;
				
			&lt;p&gt;The UCSF OEM program is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Center for Occupational and Environmental Health (COEH)&lt;/a&gt;, a multidisciplinary research and education center partnership between UCSF, UC Berkeley, and UC Davis. COEH’s mission, which aligns with the Residency and Fellowship Program’s mission, is to serve government, industry, schools, health professionals, and the general public through programs and partnerships designed to deepen understanding of occupational and environmental hazards and to prevent disease, fatalities, and injuries. Activities are grounded in multi-campus, interdisciplinary teaching programs in medicine, nursing, public health, and related fields that educate future leaders in occupational and environmental health, develop new knowledge, and bring the resources of the University of California to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The UCSF Occupational Medicine Residency and Fellowship is an integrated 2-year program in which the trainees progressively take on greater responsibility. In the first year, trainees earn a MPH or MS degree from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sph.berkeley.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UC Berkeley School of Public Health&lt;/a&gt; while also participating in a weekly clinic and other UCSF educational activities. The year at Berkeley provides excellent training in occupational and environmental epidemiology, public policy, environmental health sciences, health behavior, health education, biostatistics, ergonomics, industrial hygiene, and toxicology. Trainees attend classes and begin a research project during the first year, while also participating in clinical activities in occupational and environmental medicine at UCSF.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;For entering trainees who already have a Master’s in Public Health or other equivalent degree with appropriate coursework, the first year curriculum will include a combination of any additional ACGME-mandated academic coursework, practicum rotations, and research.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The second year is devoted to a combination of clinical experience, research, and public health practice, and involves training time in clinics; local, state, federal or international governmental agencies; NGOs; and academic, consulting and industry settings. Trainees participate in patient care activities in university and community-based clinics for occupational or environmental injuries and illnesses, infectious disease prevention services, toxicology consultations, and placement and surveillance examinations of workers. The training includes site visits to various workplace and community settings to evaluate occupational and environmental health risks.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The rotations and site visits are supplemented by weekly clinical case conferences, biweekly grand rounds, research seminars and journal clubs. Trainees also design and complete a 1-2 year research project investigating a topic of interest to them in environmental or occupational medicine. Research opportunities in occupational and environmental lung injury, ergonomics/cumulative trauma injury, neurotoxicology, injury epidemiology, heavy metal toxicity, and environmental health are available.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Depending on the interests of the trainee, the program can be tailored toward various career directions:
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Academic occupational/environmental medicine with a focus on developing a research and teaching career.
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Clinical occupational medicine focused on developing and managing a full-time clinical practice.
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Public health policy focused on understanding regulatory policy in environmental or occupational health and implementing or influencing these policies.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are actively developing opportunities in international environmental and occupational health through partners throughout the world who offer month-long rotations for our trainees.&lt;/p&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
14cme
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			&lt;br&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Save the date for our next course 2018: Thursday &amp;ndash;Saturday March 8-10 2018,&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt; Emerging and &lt;span id=&quot;0.7345869515610759&quot; class=&quot;currentHitHighlight&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Re-Emerging&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; Occupational and Environmental&amp;nbsp; Exposure and Disease and Updates in Occupational and Environmental Medicine&lt;/em&gt; including a poster abstract session Wednesday evening, March 7.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;!-- &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/cme-event-2016.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/cme-event.png&quot; class=&quot;image&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;margin-bottom:20px;margin-left:175px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;--&gt;
			&lt;div style=&quot;float:right;width:350px;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;../images/oemcollage.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:350px;&quot; class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
			&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot; style=&quot;width:360px;&quot;&gt;Poster Session, 2017 CME&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The Division of Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine offers CME courses every year. These courses are accredited for routine CME credit, but also offer Maintenance of Certification (MOC) and Qualified Medical Examiner (QME) credit. Information on the upcoming course registration will be posted at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ucsfcme.com/2018/MDM18N01/info.html#overview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UCSF CME site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Previous Courses&lt;/h3&gt;
			
			&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/cme_brochure2017.pdf&quot;&gt;Occupational and Environmental Respiratory Disease and Updates in Occupational and Environmental Medicine&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2016&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/cme_brochure2016.pdf&quot;&gt;Toxic Substances in the Workplace and the Environment and Updates in Occupational Health and Environmental Medicine&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2015&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/cme-oem-brochure2015.pdf&quot;&gt;Cardiovascular Health and Disease&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/cme_2014.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Factors in Infectious Disease&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/cme_2012.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Factors in Neurological Disease&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;2011&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/cme_2011.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Construction Industry: Old and Emerging Occupational Hazards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;2010&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/2010.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;History of Occupational and Environmental Health&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;2009&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/cme_2009.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Health and Safety in Transportation Workers: Air, Sea, and Land&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;2008&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/cme_2008.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Occupational and Environmental Respiratory Disease&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;2006&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/docs/2006.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Occupational and Environmental Medicine - including a Module on Pain Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
15fac_staff
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Faculty of the Division of Occupational and Environmental Medicine provide services in the UCSF Medical Center at Mt. Zion Occupational Medicine Faculty Practice and Multidisciplinary Clinic, at Kaiser Permanente, and at the Northern California Poison Control Center. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Our faculty has affiliations with pulmonary medicine, orthopedic surgery, toxicology, dermatology, industrial hygiene, bioengineering and occupational health nursing. Close ties are maintained with the California Department of Public Health, the California Environmental Protection Agency, the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, and the World Health Organization.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The OEM residency and fellowship program is led by Paul D. Blanc, MD, MSPH and Robert Harrison, MD, MPH.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Core Occupational Medicine Faculty&lt;/h3&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=7d0449bf99a9c76c579c8a50e83319a1&amp;name=BALMES%2CJOHN+R&quot;&gt;John Balmes, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational and Pulmonary Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Chief, Division of OEM, SFGH&lt;br /&gt;
			COEH Director&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Health effects of ozone, nitrogen dioxide and particulate matter.&lt;br /&gt; Research projects include controlled exposure chamber studies on human subjects, epidemiologic studies on air quality and asthma in Fresno, and exposures to indoor smoke from cook stoves and health effects in Guatemala.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=a6343c52cbcf26e9bbe9b6e2b21e54d7&amp;name=BLANC%2CPAUL+D&quot;&gt;Paul Blanc, MD, MSPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational and Pulmonary Medicine, Clinical Toxicology)&lt;br /&gt;
			Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Chief, Division of OEM, UCSF Medical Center&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Medical Director, San Francisco Bay Area Regional Poison Control Center&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Asthma and COPD in relation to workplace and environmental factors; occupational and environmental toxicology with a focus on pulmonary responses; the history of occupational and environmental medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=ed038116f2d49334af7f9be1a5c2354a&amp;name=HARRISON%2CROBERT+J&quot;&gt;Robert Harrison, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;(Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Occupational Medicine Clinic, UCSF-Mt. Zion&lt;br /&gt;
			Public Health Medical Officer, California Department of Public Health&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Risk factors and prevention strategies for work-related carpal tunnel syndrome, heat stress, asthma and pesticide poisoning in the California workforce; risk factors and prevention strategies for work-related fatalities.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=1084b1f89c5201f616e032d27f38fe1b&amp;name=KOSNIK%2CROBERT+EDWARD&quot;&gt;Robert Kosnik, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor Medicine&lt;br /&gt;
			Chief Occupational Health Services, UCSF &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://clinpharm.ucsf.edu/people/kolson.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kent R. Olson, MD &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Emergency Medicine and Clinical Toxicology)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine and Pharmacy, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Medical Director, San Francisco Bay Area Regional Poison Control Center&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/ProfileDetails.aspx?From=SE&amp;Person=5247275&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Patricia Quinlan, MPH, CIH&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Industrial Hygienist, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Deputy Director, COEH&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=75e7e2cfbfb20c3de3f29e025732b033&amp;name=REMPEL%2CDAVID+M&quot;&gt;David Rempel, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;(Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Professor of Medicine, UCSF	&lt;br /&gt;
			Director, Ergonomics Laboratory, UC Berkeley/UC&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Occupational ergonomics; peripheral nerve entrapment, work-related tendon disorders; hand biomechanics, tool design, workplace intervention studies.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=e1202873a16c967b69b4d6e670b69ecf&amp;name=ROISMAN%2CRACHEL+E&quot;&gt;Rachel Roisman, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Program Director, HRSA Training Enhancement Program&lt;br /&gt;
			Public Health Medical Officer, CA Department of Public Health&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sph.berkeley.edu/faculty/seward.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;James Seward, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Director, Health Services, Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory&lt;br /&gt;
			Chair, OEM Residency Advisory Committee&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Supporting UC Clinical Faculty and Other Occupational Medicine Preceptors&lt;/h3&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tom Allems, MD, MPH&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Consultant – Occupational Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Richard Cohen, MD &lt;/b&gt;(Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Consultant – Occupational Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drcraner.com/education_credentials.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;James Craner, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Consultant – Occupational Medicine
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ehib.org/person.jsp?person_key=3502&amp;eo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rupali Das, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			California Department of Public Health Occupational Health Branch&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Tracking work-related illness (with a focus on pesticide illness) to understand etiology and recommend preventive measures; measuring human exposures to chemicals though biomonitoring to reduce health effects and promote safer and more responsible chemical use policies; promoting safer alternatives to chemicals used in the home and workplace, with a special focus on pesticides.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fischmanmed.com/?page_id=20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Michael Fischman, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Medical Director, Intel Corporation&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Robert Goldberg, MD&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Medical Director, Landmark Healthcare&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://switchboard.nrdc.org/blogs/sjanssen/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sarah Janssen, MD, PhD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Urology and Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Instructor in Urology&lt;br /&gt;
			Senior Scientist, Natural Resources Defense Council&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Environmental exposures to endocrine disrupting chemicals such as phthalates, bisphenol A, and flame retardants; chemical screening and testing strategies for carcinogens and endocrine disruptors&lt;/p&gt;
				
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.permanente.net/homepage/kaiser/doctor/pauljohnson/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Paul Johnson, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Kaiser Permanente Medical Group San Francisco 
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.permanente.net/homepage/kaiser/doctor/romankownacki/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Roman Kownacki, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Medical Director, Regional Occupational Health, Kaiser Permanente&lt;br /&gt;
			Chief, Occupational Medicine, Richmond Medical Center, Kaiser Permanente&lt;/p&gt;
				
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yannick Leguyader, MD &lt;/b&gt;(Occupational Medicine) &lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Physician Diplomate, UCSF&lt;/p&gt;
				
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Peter Lichty, MD&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Medical Director, Lawrence Berkeley Lab&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/meister.htm&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Ray Meister, MD, MPH &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Public Health Medical Officer, California &lt;br /&gt;
			Department of Public Health Staff Physician, SFGH Clinic&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mark Miller, MD &lt;/b&gt; (Pediatrics)&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Director, Pediatric Environmental Health Specialty Unit&lt;br /&gt;
			Air Toxicology and Epidemiology Section, OEHHA, Cal/EPA&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; The unique susceptibility of children to environmental chemicals, particularly the impact of early life exposures on neurological and pulmonary development and associated signaling events. Recent chemicals of interest include perchlorate, secondhand smoke, and lindane. Translating new epidemiologic and toxicologic findings relevant to pediatric environmental health to the clinical audience.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Linda Morse, MD &lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Kaiser Permanente Medical Group&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/rinker.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jordan Rinker, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Private Consultant – Occupational Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanrutchik.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jonathan Rutchik, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Private Practice – Neurology and Occupational Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;
			http://uhs.berkeley.edu/students/medical/medicalstaff.shtml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Erika Schwilk, MD, MPH &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Staff Physician, Occupational Medicine&lt;br /&gt;
			University Health Services&lt;br /&gt;
			Tang Center at UC Berkeley&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=367673d6f89328cdde864c868ecd64fd&amp;name=SHUSTERMAN%2CDENNIS+J&quot;&gt;Dennis Shusterman, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Professor of Clinical Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			California Department of Public Health&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Health effects of irritant air pollutants on the upper airway, including the nose, paranasal sinuses, and vocal cords.  The effects of sidestream tobacco smoke on the upper airway. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noselab.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NoseLab&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.calepa.ca.gov/about/Bios/Solomon.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gina M. Solomon, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Deputy Secretary for Science and Health, Cal EPA&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Health effects associated with climate change, including heat waves, infectious disease shifts, and disaster response post-Katrina; Public health strategies for preparing for climate change; environmental exposure assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sph.berkeley.edu/faculty/steinmaus.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Craig Steinmaus, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Adjunct Professor, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Office of Environmental Health Hazard Assessment, Cal /EPA&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Health effects of drinking water contaminants such as arsenic and perchlorate. Meta-analysis and epidemiologic methods&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Susan Tierman, MD&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Medical Director OH NA at Johnson &amp; Johnson&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Christina Wang, MD, MPH&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Staff Physician, Kaiser Permanente Medical Group, San Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Faculty from Related Disciplines&lt;/h3&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/faculty/barbara-burgel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Barbara Burgel, RN, PhD, COHN-S, FAAN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;(Community Health Nursing)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Nursing, UCSF&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/faculty/oisaeng-hong&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Oisaeng Hong, RN, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Health Nursing)&lt;br /&gt;
			Director, Occupational Health Nursing Program, UCSF&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/faculty/soo-jeong-lee&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Soo Jeong Lee, RN, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Professor &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/faculty/dana-drew-nord&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dana Drew-Nord, RN, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Assistant Adjunct Professor &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
16grandrounds
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			&lt;h3&gt;&lt;center&gt;2017-2018 OEH Interdisciplinary Grand Rounds &lt;/center&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;strong&gt; *All OEH Grand Rounds are held at the UCSF Parnassus Campus in Moffitt Hospital, Room M-1296.&lt;/strong&gt;
			&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt; &lt;col width=&quot;80&quot;&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;background:#E6E9ED&quot;&gt; &lt;b&gt;DATE &lt;/td&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;    &lt;td style=&quot;background:#E6E9ED&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;	TYPE &lt;br&gt;GR=Grand Rounds CR=Clinical Rounds JC=Journal Club&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;background:#E6E9ED&quot;&gt;	&lt;b&gt;PRESENTER&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;background:#E6E9ED&quot;&gt; &lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;TOPIC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;
			
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=4 style=&quot;background:#efe5cd;font-weight:bold;&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;28-Sep&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br&gt;8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sam Oh, PhD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; Susceptibility factors for environmental lung disease &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	      9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;JC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Zachary Landman, MD MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	“Short-Term Absenteeism and Health Care Utilization Due to Lower Extremity Injuries Among Novice Runners: A Prospective Cohort Study.” &lt;i&gt;Clin J Sport Med&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;12-Oct&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br&gt;8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Craig Steinmaus MD, MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Arsenic in groundwater - An international problem &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	      9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;CR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jae Maldonado&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; Immigrant health and the Street Level Clinic &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;26-Oct&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Suzaynn Schick, PhD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; Health effects of e-Cigarettes &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	 9-10 AM &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;JC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jeff Meade, MD MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Journal Article Pending  	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;9-Nov&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Craig Conlon, MD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Surveillance for work-related carpal tunnel syndrome in an HMO environment 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	      9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;CR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Linda Brown, Esq&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Workers compensation law and the occupational medicine physician 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;14-Dec&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Carisa Harris-Adamson, PhD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Musculoskeletal disorders in the ageing worker &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	      9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;CR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Lee Wugofski, MD, MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; Issues in Federal occupational health &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td colspan=4 style=&quot;background:#efe5cd;font-weight:bold;&quot;&gt;&lt;center&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;25-Jan&lt;/b&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Zach Landman, MD MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Resident Presentation 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	      9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;JC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stephanie Holm, MD, MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; “Fine Particulate Air Pollution Mortality  A Nationwide Analysis in 272 Chinese Cities” &lt;i&gt;Am J Repsir Crit Care Med&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;8-Feb&lt;/b&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;John Balmes, MD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Irritant-induced asthma: Evolution of a concept &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	 9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;CR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Rich Hirsch, MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Industrial hygiene capacity building for underserved populations &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;22-Feb&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mark Miller, MD, MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Childhood leukemia and the environment 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	 9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;JC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Miguel Montoya. MD MPH &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Journal Article Pending 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;22-Mar&lt;/b&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jean Woo, MD, MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	The California Children’s Lead Poisoning Prevention Project (CLPPP)  	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	 9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;JC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pearlene Lee, MD MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Journal Article Pending 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;12-Apr&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;TBN&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Pending 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	 9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;CR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Alejandro Diaz, MD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Primary care and worker health	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;26-Apr&lt;/b&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Sam Goldman, MD MHP&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Genetic risk factors for environmentally induced neurological conditions  	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	 9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;JC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ben Schanker, MD MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Journal Article Pending	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;10-May&lt;/b&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Jeff Meade, MD MPH&lt;br&gt;Miguel Montoyo, MD MPH &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Resident Presentation 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;JC&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Joshua Potocko MD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Journal Article Pending 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;b&gt;14-Jun&lt;/b&gt; 8-9 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;GR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Stephanie Holm, MD MPH &lt;br&gt; Pearlene Lee MD MPH &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Resident Presentation 	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;	 9-10 AM	&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;CR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Patty Bilhartz, MD, MPH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	Lessons learned from a diacetyl exposure outbreak in a Texas coffee plant &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			
			&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			
			&lt;/table&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt; For an archive of the 2016-17 presentations see:&lt;a href=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/16-17_grandrounds.pdf&quot;&gt; 2016-2017 Grand Rounds (pdf)&lt;/a&gt;.
			
			&lt;br&gt;
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
17index
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			&lt;div style=&quot;float:right;width:400px;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/oemstaffgathering.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
			&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot; style=&quot;width:410px;&quot;&gt;Residents and Faculty Gathering Spring 2017&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;The University of California, San Francisco (UCSF) has been a center for training in Occupational and Environmental Medicine (OEM) since 1977. &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Graduates of our &lt;a href=&quot;/education/residency.html&quot;&gt;OEM residency program&lt;/a&gt; are leaders in environmental and occupational medicine in academics, government agencies, NGOs, and corporations. The program is accredited by ACGME and provides the knowledge and qualifications required for Board Certification in Occupational Medicine by the American Board of Preventive Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt; Hear from the UCSF  residents in the 2017 graduating class about their experiences in the program in this short video:&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/226808665&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
			
			
			&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Another educational resource is our active &lt;a href=&quot;/education/cme.html&quot;&gt;continuing medical education program&lt;/a&gt;. There is also a &lt;a href=&quot;/education/oehn.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;graduate program in occupational health nursing&lt;/a&gt; offered by the UCSF School of Nursing.&lt;/p&gt;
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
18oehn
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;UCSF Nursing students in the MS program may select the Occupational and Environmental Health Specialist (OEHS) area.  &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;For more information, please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/programs/specialties/occupational-and-environmental-health-specialist-oehs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;School of Nursing website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
19residency
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;The UCSF Occupational &amp;amp; Environmental Medicine (OEM) residency program is designed to prepare physicians for occupational and environmental medicine practice and leadership roles  in clinical, academic, government, NGO, consulting, and corporate settings. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The UCSF Occupational and Environmental Medicine (OEM) Training Program
			prepares physicians for occupational and environmental medicine practice and leadership roles including in clinical, academic, governmental units, NGOs, consulting, and corporate settings. The Program provides academic didactic instruction, clinical and non-clinical proctored? experiences, and research opportunities. A large core and affiliated faculty based at UCSF, together with extramural clinical faculty and other preceptors, and our faculty partners in nursing, industrial hygiene, and ergonomics, provide this training. Graduates of the UCSF OEM Program are currently leaders in all of the practice settings listed above. Trainees will achieve competency in all core knowledge content areas in OEM, and are encouraged to develop areas of special expertise. In keeping with this goal, the educational program is individually tailored to meet the needs of each trainee. The UCSF OEM Program was founded in 1979, and is fully accredited by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acgme.org/acgmeweb/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education (ACGME)&lt;/a&gt; for up to eight trainees.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The UCSF OEM program is housed within the  &lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Center for Occupational and Environmental Health (COEH)&lt;/a&gt;, a multidisciplinary research and education center partnership between UCSF, UC Berkeley, and UC Davis. COEH’s mission, which aligns with the Residency and Fellowship Program’s mission, is to serve government, industry, schools, health professionals, and the general public through programs and partnerships designed to deepen understanding of occupational and environmental hazards and to prevent disease, fatalities, and injuries. Activities are grounded in multi-campus, interdisciplinary teaching programs in medicine, nursing, public health, and related fields that educate future leaders in occupational and environmental health, develop new knowledge, and bring the resources of the University of California to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;In addition to the traditional OEM residency program track, which is funded through support from the CDC National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH), we also offer an innovative and unique training track focused on vulnerable workers and occupational health disparities.  This track in the residency is funded by the federal Health Resources and Services Agency (HRSA) and is one of three HRSA supported OEM programs in the country and the only one with this focus. Trainees in this track will fulfill all the ACGME requirements of our larger residency. In addition, however, this special program concentration offers the opportunity for additional clinical activities, public health field work, policy work, and didactic content relevant to low wage and vulnerable working populations as well as issues of environmental social justice. Specific examples may include work with California State agencies, outreach through the Labor Occupational Health Program at UC Berkeley, field experience with the Natural Resources Defense Council, and clinical service in community clinics serving migrant and day laborers and other uninsured and/or low wage workers.
			 &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/oemresidents.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:350px;&quot; class=&quot;imgRight&quot; alt=&quot;oemresidents&quot;&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Program Plan/Curriculum&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;The UCSF Occupational Medicine Residency and Fellowship is an integrated 2-year program in
			which the trainees progressively take on greater responsibility and achieve core competency in the areas delineated by the American College of Preventive Medicine and the American Conference on Graduate Medical Education (ACGME). In the first year, trainees typically complete coursework to earn a MPH or MS degree from the  &lt;a href=&quot;http://sph.berkeley.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UC Berkeley School of Public Health&lt;/a&gt; while also participating in a weekly clinic and other UCSF clinical activities to meet ACGME requirements for 4 months of clinical activity per year. In certain circumstances, the MPH/MS training may occur later in the training cycle. For entering trainees who already have a Master’s in Public Health or other equivalent degree, the first year curriculum will include a combination of clinical work (total 4 months) as well as other non-clinical rotations. The second year is devoted to a combination of clinical experience (four months), non-clinical rotations, and research. Residents entering the program who have completed a Master’s in Public Health or other equivalent degree as well as a primary residency such as Internal Medicine, Family Medicine, or Preventive Medicine, may be considered for matriculation into the second year of the residency and thus eligible to complete AGME approved training in Occupational Medicine in one year.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;A typical representative breakdown of the trainees’ activities by year is shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;table&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;background:#EFE5CD;font-weight:bold;&quot;&gt;First Year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;background:#EFE5CD;font-weight:bold;&quot;&gt;Second Year&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 month of special programming (August) including industrial hygiene site visits and clinical work plus didactic training
			&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1 month of special programming including industrial hygiene site visits and clinical work plus didactic training  &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;8 months UC Berkeley SPH coursework&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;	&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Weekly half-day clinic throughout year and 3 weeks of occupational clinical needlestick hotline coverage (nights and weekends)&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;Weekly half-day clinic throughout year and 3 weeks of occupational clinical needlestick hotline coverage (nights and weekends)&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			
			&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2 1/2 months of full-time clinical rotations (July; mid-May through June)
				&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;2 1/2 to 4  months of clinical rotations&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			
				&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1-4months non-clinical rotations including corporate/consulting  and public and environmental health  rotations&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
				&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				2 months research&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;/tr&gt;
			&lt;/table&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The special August program features industrial hygiene site visits. Theses site visits are constituted as an Industrial Hygiene (IH) curriculum and include a range of industrial sites and non-industrial workplaces, as well as environmental health site visits with written assessments of sites and their IH aspects. The summer training also includes selected didactic work through the Center for Occupational and Environmental Health (COEH) “Summer Institute” which further strengthens industrial hygiene training as well as other topics such as risk communication. At the site visits, the trainees are expected to observe and record occupational and environmental hazards and the corresponding control measures. Each trainee is expected to do preparatory research prior to at least two of the site visits, and to brief their colleagues on the occupational and environmental health issues related to that industry. In addition, each trainee is expected to do at least two write-ups after the site visits to summarize the hazards and risks, and to communicate recommendations. Site visits include a wide range of industries and environmental sites in the greater San Francisco Bay Area. Examples include: refineries, metals manufacturing, foundries, cement manufacturing, pharmaceutical and biotech facilities, research laboratories, sewage treatment facilities, waste handling facilities, distribution centers, food processing, dairies, farms, wineries, nail salons, construction sites, maintenance of the Golden Gate Bridge and airlines. There are 10-12 site visits during the month of August. Additional visits also may occur in July when grand rounds are in recess. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;In August of either the first or second year, trainees also take the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.epibiostat.ucsf.edu/courses/summerworkshop.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Training in Clinical Research (TICR) Summer Workshop at UCSF&lt;/a&gt; which provides grounding in applied biostatistics, epidemiology, and clinical study design.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Throughout both residency years, trainees acquire skills in clinical occupational medicine through participation in weekly half-day clinics and an associated clinical conference. They also attend the bimonthly OEM Grand Rounds, followed by either Journal Club or a Clinical Seminar in which faculty share unusual or challenging management issues. Trainees are expected to present at least one or two journal club article during the course of the year. During this year, the trainees are expected to choose a research project and research mentor and to begin work on a project that will be completed during the second year.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;For more information on UC Berkeley School of Public Health:
			&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sph.berkeley.edu/graduate-degrees/degrees-we-offer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Academic Programs&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ehs.sph.berkeley.edu/current/req_mph.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MPH degree requirements&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ehs.sph.berkeley.edu/current/handbook.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Student Handbooks for MPH and MS programs&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;The residency/fellowship program has multiple clinic sites where ongoing training of OEM trainees occurs during both years of the program. The Occupational and Environmental Medicine Clinic at UCSF/Mt. Zion is a weekly half-day clinic that provides an opportunity to evaluate complex patients with environmental or occupational health issues (as noted above). Other ongoing clinical opportunities include the SF Kaiser Permanente Occupational Medicine Clinic at Opera Plaza, the San Francisco Veterans Affairs Medical Center (SFVAMC), the San Francisco Division of the California State Poison Control System, and a multi-site subspecialty rotation that includes dermatology, pulmonary function, neurology, complementary medicine, allergy, and ophthalmology. Another clinical opportunity occurs through the Pediatric Environmental Health Specialty Unit (PEHSU). The PEHSU is funded by the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry (ATSDR) and the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency through a cooperative agreement with the Association of Occupational and Environmental Clinics (AOEC). The PEHSU is a collaboration between the Division of OEM, the Northern California Poison Control Center, and the UCSF Department of Pediatrics. The PEHSU is directed by Dr. Sam Goldman, a Preventive Medicine specialist and Dr. Mark Miller, a pediatrician. A primary function of the PEHSU is education and outreach to community physicians. Our program in Northern California also provides consultative services, by telephone and in our clinic, for pediatric environmental health problems.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Trainees are evaluated semi-annually based on how well they have achieved goals and objectives for each aspect of training through our ACGME-mandated Clinical Competency Committee (CCC) chaired by the Associate Program Director. Each resident is evaluated based on 26ACGME specified Milestones (see attached). Evaluative input includes rotation-based evaluations, self-evaluations, other faculty input, patient evaluations, 360° evaluations, and resident-maintained portfolios. The UCSF electronic system (MedHub) is used to facilitate evaluation of trainees and faculty.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;In addition to the CCC, a Program Evaluation Committee (the PEC, which includes one of the current residents) assesses all of the components of the Residency curriculum including rotations and coursework. Both the CCC and the PEC report to the Residency Advisory Committee that meets two times each year to integrate their input, along with other data such as structured residency and faculty surveys. The overall evaluation of each Resident is the responsibility of the Program and Associate Directors, who determine with RAC oversight whether the Resident successfully completes the program.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Interdisciplinary Experiences&lt;/h3&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The faculty of the OEM Program at UCSF approach occupational and environmental health teaching, research, and service activities from an interdisciplinary perspective. Whenever possible, interdisciplinary training opportunities with occupational and environmental health nurses (OEHN) and industrial hygienists (IH) are developed.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Paul Blanc, MD and Sandra Domeracki NP co-direct a course for both the nursing students and OEM trainees. Trainees are required to take this UCSF course entitled “Management of Clinical Occupational Health Problems”, N271.06 (offered every other year, e.g., once during the two year training period). Trainees are also required to take a similar joint nursing-medicine medical toxicology course taught by Sam Goldman, MD. A yearly post-graduate course offered by the Division of Occupational and Environmental Medicine includes approximately 18 CME hour equivalents. The COEH Summer Institute as noted previously also occurs each year. All of these efforts are interdisciplinary.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;The program has many other activities where interdisciplinary interaction occurs regularly. The &lt;a href=&quot;/care&quot;&gt;Occupational and Environmental Medicine Clinic at Mt Zion&lt;/a&gt;  includes OEM, OEHN and IH trainees in the evaluation of patients and their workplaces. Workplace site visits, grand rounds, research seminars, and case conference have participants from multiple disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;Joint Occupational Environmental Medicine training opportunities exist with UCSF  programs in both Pulmonary Critical Care and Medical Toxicology and can be explored on a case-by-case basis. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Research Training&lt;/h3&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Training in research methods and development of research projects is a vital element of our program. The program seeks trainees who will advance the scientific knowledge base upon which the prevention and treatment of occupational disease rests, as well as those who will educate future generations of researchers. Trainees are expected to identify a research mentor in their first year of training and begin a project that will be completed in the second year. The course   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.epibiostat.ucsf.edu/courses/summerworkshop.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Training in Clinical Research (TICR)&lt;/a&gt; through the Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics at UCSF already has been mentioned above. In this course, trainees are required to develop and present the design and protocol for a relevant research project. Additional training is provided in the monthly Journal Club, which has a special emphasis on epidemiological and statistical methodology. Principal faculty research mentors include Drs. Blanc, Balmes, and Steinmaus, as well as others. There are a large number of other supporting and core faculty members who sponsor trainee research activities and regularly participate in the research-training program through various interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Who Should Apply&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/oemresidents2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:180px;&quot; class=&quot;imgRight&quot; alt=&quot;oemresidents&quot;&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;Physicians who have had primary care training (usually internal medicine, family medicine, emergency medicine) and are interested in opportunities for academic, government, or community careers in occupational and environmental medicine. Physicians who have only completed a clinical postgraduate year (PGY 1), but who  demonstrate a strong commitment to occupational or environmental medicine will also be considered. Combined training programs with pulmonary medicine and with medical toxicology are also available.&lt;/p&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
20index
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			
			&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;masters&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;First Year of Fellowship  Training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Master’s at  U.C. Berkeley School of Public Health &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;All  first year OEM residents and fellows attend the School  of Public Health at the University of California  at Berkeley to  obtain a Masters degree (MPH or MS) in Environmental Health Sciences or  Epidemiology. The school year at Berkeley  covers two semesters beginning in August and ending in May.&amp;nbsp; Required coursework includes biostatistics,  epidemiology, health services organization and administration, environmental and  occupational health, and social and behavioral influences on health.&amp;nbsp; For the MPH, a minimum of 42 units and a  passing score on the comprehensive exam is required for graduation.&amp;nbsp; The Curriculum for the MS degree is similar,  but trainees may take fewer course units and are expected to complete a  research project rather than take an examination. The research project can be  completed over the first 18 months of training.&lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample  Curriculum:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall:&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;           
			        PH 142A &lt;strong&gt;Probability  &amp;amp; Statistics&lt;/strong&gt; (Required) 4  units&lt;br&gt;           
			          PH 200C &lt;strong&gt;Overview  of Public Health&lt;/strong&gt; (Required) 2 units&lt;br&gt;           
			        PH 250A &lt;strong&gt;Epidemiologic  Methods&lt;/strong&gt; (Required)&amp;nbsp;4  units&lt;br&gt;
			        PH 269E&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Topics in Environmental Medicine +  Seminar&lt;/strong&gt; (Required)&amp;nbsp;3 units&lt;br&gt;           
			        PH 297&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Field Study&lt;/strong&gt; (Clinic)&amp;nbsp;3 units&lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spring: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;           
			        PH 200D&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Integrative  Breadth Course&lt;/strong&gt; (Required)&amp;nbsp;2 units&lt;br&gt;           
			        PH 270B&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Toxicology&lt;/strong&gt; (Required)&amp;nbsp;3 units&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;           
			        PH 269C &lt;strong&gt;Ergonomics&lt;/strong&gt; (Required)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;4 units&lt;br&gt;           
			        PH 297 &lt;strong&gt;Field Study &lt;/strong&gt;(Clinic)&amp;nbsp;3 units&lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advanced  Courses/Electives:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;           
			        PH  254B &lt;strong&gt;Advanced Occupational &amp;amp;  Environ Epidemiology&lt;/strong&gt; 3 units&lt;br&gt;
			        PH 271 &lt;strong&gt;Environmental Science and Policy&lt;/strong&gt; 3  units&lt;br&gt;           
			          PH 270A &lt;strong&gt;Exposure  Assessment and Control&lt;/strong&gt; 3  units&lt;br&gt;           
			          PH 220 &lt;strong&gt;Health  Risk Assessment &lt;/strong&gt;4  units&lt;br&gt;           
			        PH 272A &lt;strong&gt;GIS  and Remote Sensing&lt;/strong&gt; 3 Units&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;clinic&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Weekly Clinic,  Rounds, and Seminars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;Fellows  participate in clinic for a half-day per week throughout both years of  training. Clinic may be at the Occupational and Environmental Medicine Clinic  at UCSF, at the Kaiser Occupational Medicine Clinic, or at the Tang Center  Ergonomics Clinic at Berkeley.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Occupational  and Environmental Medicine Clinic at UCSF/ Mount Zion &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;           
			        Cases  include referrals for occupational and environmental exposures, toxicology, and  complex musculoskeletal disorders. Some families and pediatric cases are seen in  collaboration with our Pediatric Environmental Health Specialty Unit.  Industrial hygiene and nursing students also participate in patient  evaluations, as does our faculty Industrial Hygienist. Faculty attendings in  this clinic include Drs. Solomon, Jewell, Fischman, Goldberg, Born, Das, and  Rinker.&lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ergonomics  Clinic at UC Berkeley   Tang Center&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;           
			        Evaluation  and management of upper body musculoskeletal cases with Dr. David Rempel.&lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kaiser&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Opera Plaza&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; Occupational Medicine Clinic &lt;br&gt;
			        &lt;/em&gt;Primary  occupational medicine clinic services under the direction of Dr. Paul Johnson.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Fellows  also attend Grand Rounds, Journal Club, and Research Seminar on every 2nd  &amp;amp; 4th Thursday morning. Case conference occurs on Thursdays  immediately preceding clinic at UCSF.&lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;Fellows  also are on call to cover the UCSF needle-stick hotline for 4-6 weeks during  both years of training. Calls are taken from home at night and on weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;rotations&quot; name=&quot;rotations&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Second Year of Fellowship  Training&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Clinical  Rotations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;        &lt;em&gt;A minimum of  two months must be devoted to clinical rotations. Additional elective months  may also be spent at these sites. Additional clinical months will be required  for residents or fellows who have had limited prior clinical training. In most  cases, at least one month must include full-time occupational medicine at  Kaiser or CPMC.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Kaiser  Permanente Medical Group - Occupational Medicine Clinic. &lt;/u&gt;General primary  occupational medicine services with an emphasis on musculoskeletal evaluations  and ergonomic issues. Location: San    Francisco, CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;California&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt; Pacific Medical   Center&lt;/u&gt; (CPMC). A busy  comprehensive occupational health service that provides consultation and  medical surveillance for occupational and environmental hazards, evaluation and  treatment of work related injuries and illnesses, and case management. Location:  San Francisco, CA.        UCSF Ergonomics. This  rotation includes onsite ergonomic assessments, evaluation of musculoskeletal  disorders, orthopedics, and medical management. Location: Tang Center,  U.C. Berkeley.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Lawrence&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt; Berkeley Lab, Health  Services Department&lt;/u&gt; &amp;nbsp;(Clinical focus). National laboratory with  extensive health services and research activities. The rotation includes  occupational health services for employees, ergonomic and industrial hazard  evaluations; learning about safety and industrial hygiene programs; health  promotion, disease prevention, employee assistance programs; and workers  compensation management. Location: Berkeley,   CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Lawrence  Livermore National Laboratory, Health Services Department (LLNL) (Clinical  focus). &lt;/u&gt;LLNL  is a Research and Development Laboratory with a focus on national security  issues.&amp;nbsp; The Health Services Department  serves over 7000 employees and provides comprehensive clinical and consultative  services, including medical surveillance, evaluation and treatment of  work-related injuries and illnesses, ergonomic, safety, and industrial hygiene  evaluations, health promotion, employee assistance programs, and workers  compensation management.&amp;nbsp; LLNL has many  interesting and unusual occupational health issues ranging from beryllium to  biological agents and radiation. Location: Livermore, CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Jonathan  Rutchik, MD&lt;/u&gt;.  Neurotoxicology private practice, consulting and medico-legal work. Location: Mill Valley, CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;SF  Regional Poison Control   Center&lt;/u&gt; (PCC). Physician  and pharmacologist teams advise physicians and the public regarding toxic  ingestions (including medication adverse effects), skin and inhalation  exposures.&amp;nbsp; Consult on in-patient  toxicology cases at San Francisco    General Hospital,  and provide telephone consultations on toxicology cases at other hospitals.  Location: San Francisco, CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Pediatric  Environmental Health Specialty Unit (PEHSU)&lt;/u&gt;. This program is part of the OEM  Division at SFGH, in partnership with the Northern California   Poison Control   Center and the UCSF  Department of Pediatrics. The PEHSU responds to calls from clinicians and the  public about pediatric environmental exposures, performs outreach and education  to primary care pediatrics providers, and participates in the multidisciplinary  clinic at UCSF/Mt. Zion when children or families with environmental exposures  are evaluated. Location: San Francisco,   CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;phrotations&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Public Health  Rotations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;
			      &lt;/strong&gt;        &lt;em&gt;A minimum of  two months must be devoted to public health rotations. Fellows may elect to  spend two sequential months at one site, or may rotate through two different  sites. Fellows interested in public health may spend additional elective months  at any of these sites.&lt;/em&gt;        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;California  Department of Public Health - Occupational Health Branch (OHB). &lt;/u&gt;The OHB is a  public health program to identify and evaluate workplace hazards, track  patterns of work-related injury and illness, develop training and informational  materials, provide technical assistance to prevent work-related injury and  illness, and recommend protective occupational health standards. Programs  include the: (1) Hazard Evaluation System and Information Service (HESIS) which  evaluates hazards to provide information and technical assistance on new or  unappreciated hazards; (2) Occupational Health Surveillance and Evaluation  Program (OHSEP) which conducts research on work-related illness, injury and  death in California; (3) Occupational Lead Poisoning Prevention Program (OLPPP)  which provides information and assistance to identify lead hazards and prevent  work-related lead poisoning; and (4) California Safe Cosmetics Program (CSCP)  which collects and provides information on hazardous ingredients in cosmetic  products sold in California. Location: Richmond,   CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;California&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt; Department of Public  Health/Environmental Health Investigations Branch&lt;/u&gt; (EHIB). EHIB  works to protect the health of Californians by studying how the environment  affects health and by educating and informing the public. EHIB units include:  (1) Community Participation and Education Section; (2) Exposure Assessment  Section; (3) Environmental Epidemiology Section; (4) Site Assessment Section.  The California Environmental Contaminant Biomonitoring Program is run by staff  at EHIB. &lt;br&gt;
			      Location:  Richmond, CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;California&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt; EPA &amp;ndash; Office  of Environmental Health Hazard Assessment (OEHHA). &lt;/u&gt;OEHHA is  responsible for developing and providing risk managers in state and local  government agencies with toxicological and medical information relevant to  decisions involving public health. OEHHA’s responsibilities include: (1)  Developing health-protective exposure standards for different media (air,  water, land) to recommend to regulatory agencies, including ambient air quality  standards for the Air Resources Board and drinking water chemical contaminant  standards for the Department of Health Services; (2) Carrying out special  investigations of potential environmental causes of illness, diseases and deaths;  (3) Making recommendations with respect to sport and commercial fishing in  areas where fish may be contaminated; (4) Assessing health risks to the public  from air pollution, pesticide and other chemical contamination of food,  seafood, drinking water, and consumer products; (5) Providing guidance to local  agencies with specific public health problems, including appropriate actions to  take in emergencies that may involve chemicals; (6) Implementing the provisions  of the Safe Drinking Water and Toxic Enforcement Act of 1986 (Proposition  65).&amp;nbsp; Location: Oakland, CA.&amp;nbsp;        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Natural  Resources Defense Council (NRDC)&lt;/u&gt;. The goal of this NGO is to preserve the  environment and protect public health through education and advocacy. Areas of  focus include diesel exhaust exposure reduction; reduction of greenhouse gases  and conventional pollutants from refineries, cement kilns, and mobile sources;  reducing lead and mercury pollution; pesticide policy reform; drinking water  regulation; and identification and elimination of endocrine disrupting  chemicals in consumer products.&amp;nbsp; &lt;br&gt;
			      Location:  San Francisco, CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Safety  and Health Assessment and Research for Prevention Program (SHARP).&lt;/u&gt; Research in  occupational safety and health, surveillance of occupational health and  hazards, assessment of emerging conditions, and cluster investigation. SHARP  also provides research support for occupational health standard-setting in Washington State. SHARP has special emphasis is  placed on ergonomics issues. Location: Olympia,   WA.        National Institute for Occupational Safety and  Health (NIOSH). The Federal agency devoted to  industry investigations and research and education in Occupational Medicine.  The rotation is with the Hazard Evaluations and Technical Assistance Branch  (HETAB) medical section. Activities include participating in worksite health  hazard evaluations, responding to inquiries from the public, and participating  in NIOSH research projects and seminars. Location: Cincinnati, OH.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;California&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt; OSHA&lt;/u&gt;. State  consultation and enforcement services for California OSHA regulations with  offices throughout CA.&amp;nbsp; Center of Operation:  San Francisco.  CA.&amp;nbsp;        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Federal  OSHA&lt;/u&gt;.  Development and application of occupational health policy at the national  level. Work developing OSHA regulations, assisting in compliance  investigations, answering inquiries from the public, and developing Safety and  Health Information Bulletins. Location: Washington   DC.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;World  Health Organization, Occupational Health Branch.&lt;/u&gt; WHO is  implementing a global strategy to provide scientific policy, legislation and  support to decision-makers, estimate the magnitude of the burden of  occupational diseases and injuries, provide infrastructure support and  development through capacity building, information dissemination and  networking, and support protection and promotion of workers' health. &amp;nbsp;Location: Geneva, Switzerland.        &lt;/p&gt;
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;corprotations&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Corporate/Consulting/Administrative  Rotations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;        &lt;br&gt;
			      &lt;em&gt;A minimum of  two months is normally devoted to rotations in this category. Fellows  interested in this type of practice may spend additional elective months at any  of these sites.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;The  Permanente Medical Group - Kaiser Permanente Northern California Administrative  Offices&lt;/u&gt;.  A non-clinical rotation that focuses on learning how Worker’s Compensation  Utilization Review is performed, how MPN networks are developed, managed and  sold from inside a large HMO. Location: Oakland,   CA&lt;u&gt;&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Lawrence&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt; Berkeley Lab, Health  Services Department&lt;/u&gt; &amp;nbsp;(Corporate focus). National laboratory with  extensive health services and research activities in Berkeley.&amp;nbsp;  The rotation will include ergonomic and industrial hazard evaluations;  learning about safety and industrial hygiene programs; health promotion,  disease prevention, employee assistance programs; and workers compensation  management. Location: Berkeley,   CA.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt; &lt;u&gt;Lawrence  Livermore National Laboratory, Health Services Department (LLNL) (Corporate  focus). &lt;/u&gt;LLNL  is a Research and Development Laboratory with a focus on national security  issues.&amp;nbsp; The Health Services Department  serves over 7000 employees and provides comprehensive clinical and consultative  services, including medical surveillance, ergonomic, safety, and industrial  hygiene evaluations, health promotion, employee assistance programs, and  workers compensation management.&amp;nbsp; LLNL  has many interesting and unusual occupational health issues ranging from  beryllium to biological agents and radiation. Location: Livermore, CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Richard  Cohen MD, MPH, Inc. &lt;/u&gt;Consultant to companies in biotechnology and pharmaceutical research and  manufacturing, semiconductor equipment and microprocessor  production, healthcare supplies and equipment manufacturing, and electronic  equipment research and development. Location: South San   Francisco, Peninsula, and North    Bay areas (requires a car and willingness to travel).&amp;nbsp;        State Compensation Insurance Fund (SCIF). The rotation will provide the participating Fellow  with an understanding of the roles/responsibilities of medical professionals  working within a large workers compensation insurance carrier and an  appreciation for managed care from the payer’s perspective.&amp;nbsp; There is also an opportunity to learn about  the research potential of a large administrative database. Location: San Francisco, CA.        &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;electives&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Elective  Rotations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
			&lt;/strong&gt;        &lt;em&gt;Electives may  be taken from the rotations listed above, or from those below.&amp;nbsp; If the resident/fellow is interested in  developing a new elective rotation that is not on this list, the rotation must  be arranged and approved by the Program Director at least three months in advance  so that a signed letter of agreement can be put in place.&lt;/em&gt;        &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;James  Craner, MD, MPH&lt;/u&gt;. A consultant to gaming, mining, various other industries  with clinical practices throughout the state of Nevada.&amp;nbsp;  Location: Reno, NV.        &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Jordan Rinker,MD, MPH&lt;/u&gt;. Consulting Medical Director to pharmaceutical  research and manufacturing, biotechnology, medical center occupational health  companies. Location: Various Sites in Bay Area.        &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Michael  Kosnett, MD. &lt;/u&gt;Medical toxicology private practice, and medico-legal work,  specializing in the toxicity of metals. Location: Denver, CO.        &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Chevron&lt;/u&gt;. Management  and evaluation of occupational and environmental health programs within one of  the world’s largest energy companies. Fitness for work issues, multinational  and multicultural industrial medicine including travel medicine and  international OEM issues, worker’s comp and disability, surveillance, and an  understanding of industry-specific hazards. Location: Houston, TX.        &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Central  Labor Institute, Mumbai, India. &lt;/u&gt;Opportunity to  spend time at a variety of factories and observe working conditions first-hand  in India.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Workshops, trainings, and conferences  for physicians. Opportunity to learn about  occupational health surveillance and injury prevention in Asian and Pacific  countries, and to develop protocols and educational materials. Location: Sion, Mumbai, India.        &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;National&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt; Taiwan University&lt;/u&gt;&lt;u&gt;. &lt;/u&gt;Academic  occupational medicine residency training program in Taiwan, with clinical sites,  consulting practices with local industry, and ongoing research opportunities.  Fellows attend grand rounds, research conferences, case conferences, and  industry site visits with faculty and trainees from NTU, and have the  opportunity to see injured workers in clinic. Location: Taipei, Taiwan.        &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;research&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Research project&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;        &lt;br&gt;
			  A  research project is a required component of the training. Projects typically  span most of the year with a full-time block of 1-2 months for in-depth  work.&amp;nbsp; The research results must be  submitted to peer review either as an abstract for a poster presentation at a  conference, or as a manuscript for a scientific journal. Typically, Fellows  submit an abstract to the American Occupational Health Conference in July of  their second year for presentation at the conference the following Spring. In  addition, the results must be presented at a UCSF OEM Grand Rounds. Competitive  funding for research project expenses is available through the Targeted  Research Training (TRT) grants at COEH. Applications are due in September for  these grants, and trainees are strongly encouraged to apply.        Examples  of recent research projects include: &lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;ul type=&quot;disc&quot;&gt;
			          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;            Guntur, S&lt;/strong&gt;. “In       Utero and Childhood Arsenic Exposure and Life-Long Impacts on Lung       Function and Disease” &lt;/li&gt;
			          &lt;li&gt;            &lt;strong&gt;Jew S.&lt;/strong&gt; “Assessment       of Hazard Exposures Using Survey Analysis in the Nail Salon Workplace: A Pilot       Study of Nail Salon Workers in the San Francisco Bay       Area” &lt;/li&gt;
			          &lt;li&gt;            &lt;strong&gt;Arredondo       S. &lt;/strong&gt;“Job Strain and Health Related Quality of Life in Las Vegas Hotel Room       Cleaners” &lt;/li&gt;
			          &lt;li&gt;            &lt;strong&gt;Gallagher       M.&lt;/strong&gt; “Clinical evaluation of a surface electromyography system for upper       extremity soft tissue injury” &lt;/li&gt;
			      &lt;/ul&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
21research
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
22tutorials
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
23apply
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			 &lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Applications can be submitted via the  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aamc.org/services/eras/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Electronic Residency Application Service (ERAS)&lt;/a&gt;. Application materials must be posted on ERAS by October 15th to receive full consideration.  &lt;/p&gt;
			
			 &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Questions about our application process can be directed to the program coordinator at: &lt;/i&gt;
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Occupational Medicine Residency Program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			VAMC Veterans Affairs Medical Center&lt;br /&gt;
			4150 Clement Street, Room 1A85&lt;br /&gt;
			San Francisco, CA 94143-0111 &lt;br /&gt;
			Fax: (415) 750-2182&lt;br /&gt;
			Tel: (415)  221-4810 Ext 2-6592&lt;br /&gt;
			Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:lucia.wang@ucsf.edu&quot;&gt;lucia.wang@ucsf.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Program number: 380-05-77-059&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;Earliest date we review: September 15th&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Closing date we review: November 6th &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Interview dates if invited: September 26th through November 20th 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
					  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electronic Residency Application Service (ERAS):&lt;/strong&gt; Our program is listed under Preventive Medicine residencies. ERAS permits applicants to compile their application materials in a central secure web location such that each of their selected training programs can access the documents directly. There is a fee to applicants for this service. For more general information about ERAS visit:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aamc.org/students/eras/start.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.aamc.org/students/eras/start.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All applicants to the program who do not already possess an MPH must also complete a  &lt;em&gt;separate &lt;a href=&quot;http://grad.berkeley.edu/admissions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to the UC Berkeley School of Public Health MPH (or MS) degree program.  &lt;/strong&gt;The deadline for this application is typically early December.&lt;/p&gt;
				  &lt;p&gt;Applications are complete when we have: (1) a completed application form, with a one-page essay statement describing your interest in occupational and/or environmental medicine; (2) a certified original copy of your medical school transcript; and (3) a Dean's letter and three letters of recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
24contact
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;Questions about our program may be directed to:&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Occupational Medicine Residency Program, Department of Medicine&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			University of California, San Francisco&lt;br /&gt;
			San Francisco General Hospital &lt;br /&gt;
			SFVAMC  Box 0111&lt;br /&gt;
			4150 Clement Street&lt;br /&gt; 
			 San Francisco, CA 94121&lt;br /&gt;
			 Tel: (415) 221-4810 ext 26592 &lt;/p&gt;
			 
			 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
			Residency Program Coordinator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			 Lucia Wang&lt;br /&gt;
			 Tel: (415) 221-4810 ext 26592&lt;br /&gt;
			 Email:  &lt;a href=&quot;Lucia.Wang@ucsf.edu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lucia.Wang@ucsf.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
25curriculum
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			
			&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;masters&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Master's at UC Berkeley School of Public Health&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top:-15px;&quot;&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;All OEM trainees without an MPH or equivalent degree attend the UC Berkeley School of Public Health to obtain a master’s degree (MPH) through its  &lt;a href=&quot;http://sph.berkeley.edu/areas-study/interdisciplinary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Interdisciplinary Studies track&lt;/a&gt; (in some cases an MPH in Epidemiology or an MS  or MPH in Environmental Health Sciences, but such exceptions should be discussed and approved by  the Residency Program prior to application to the School of Public Health for its December 1 deadline).&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;For the MPH, a minimum of 42 units and a passing score on the comprehensive exam is required for graduation. The curriculums for the MS degree is similar, but with fewer credit hours required and trainees are expected to complete a research project rather than take an examination. The research project can be completed in the summer or fall following the academic year, if needed.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt; Sample MPH Curriculum&lt;/h3&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
			        PH 142A &lt;strong&gt;Probability  &amp;amp; Statistics&lt;/strong&gt; (Required) 4  units&lt;br&gt;
			          PH 200 C1 &lt;strong&gt;Health Policy and Management &lt;/strong&gt; (Required) 2 units&lt;br&gt;
			        PH 250A &lt;strong&gt;Epidemiologic  Methods&lt;/strong&gt; (Required) 4  units&lt;br&gt;
			        PH 270 &lt;strong&gt;Introduction to Environmental Health Sciences (Required)&lt;/strong&gt; (Required) 3 units&lt;br&gt;
			        PH 297 &lt;strong&gt;Field Study&lt;/strong&gt; (Clinic) 3 units&lt;br&gt;
			        &lt;i&gt;3 additional units of electives&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spring: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			        PH 200 C2 &lt;strong&gt;Health and Social Behavior &lt;/strong&gt; (Required) 2 units&lt;br&gt;
			        PH 270B &lt;strong&gt;Toxicology&lt;/strong&gt; (Required) 3 units &lt;br&gt;
			        PH 269C &lt;strong&gt;Ergonomics&lt;/strong&gt; (Required) 4 units&lt;br&gt;
			        PH 297 &lt;strong&gt;Field Study&lt;/strong&gt; (Clinic) 3 units&lt;br&gt;
			        PH 271E &lt;strong&gt;Science and Policy for Environmental Health  &lt;/strong&gt; 3 units&lt;br&gt;
			        &lt;i&gt;A course in health services organization and administration, and 3 additional units of electives&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advanced  Courses/Electives:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			       &lt;b&gt; (Notes: electives must include at least 1 additional unit of behavioral health and 1 unit of health care management/organization)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			        PH 269E &lt;b&gt;Topics in Environmental Medicine&lt;/b&gt; 2 or 3 units&lt;br /&gt;
			PH 254B &lt;b&gt;Advanced Occupational &amp; Environmental Epi&lt;/b&gt; 3 units&lt;br /&gt;
			PH 270A &lt;b&gt;Exposure Assessment and Control&lt;/b&gt; 3 units&lt;br /&gt;
			PH 220 &lt;b&gt;Health Risk Assessment&lt;/b&gt; 4 units&lt;br /&gt;
			PH 272A &lt;b&gt;GIS and Remote Sensing&lt;/b&gt; 4 units&lt;br /&gt;
			PH 272B &lt;b&gt;Case Studies in Occupational and Environmental Epi&lt;/b&gt; 2 units&lt;br /&gt;
			PH 288C &lt;b&gt;Prev Med Seminar Clinical Preventive Medicine&lt;/b&gt; 1 unit&lt;br /&gt;
			PH 288D &lt;b&gt;Prev Med Seminar Health Care Management/Organization&lt;/b&gt; 1 unit
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Summer Didactics&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Prior to the start of the fall semester at Berkeley, there is a program of site visits in August in which both first and second year trainees participate, as do Medical Toxicology trainees and other guests such as Occupational Health Nursing students, medical students, and visiting scholars, depending on site availability. The site visits rotate on a 2-year cycle. Summer session content taken over the two years of the program also fulfills graduate level coursework requirements and address benchmarks in industrial hygiene and in risk/hazard control and communication.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;clinic&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Weekly Clinic,  Rounds, and Seminars&lt;/h3&gt;
			     &lt;p&gt;  Trainees participate in clinic for a half-day per week throughout both years of the program. Clinic is typically at the Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine Clinic at Mount Zion, although sessions the Kaiser Permanente Occupational Medicine Clinic in San Francisco may also fulfill this commitment depending on scheduling needs. Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine Clinic at UCSF Mount Zion &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Cases include referrals for occupational and environmental exposures, toxicology, and complex musculoskeletal disorders. Some families and pediatric cases are seen in collaboration with our Pediatric Environmental Health Specialty Unit. Industrial hygiene and nursing students also participate in patient evaluations, as does our faculty Industrial Hygienist.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Trainees also attend Grand Rounds, Journal Club, and Clinical Practice Presentations on every 2nd and 4th Thursday morning. In addition, case conference occurs midday Mondays at the Mount Zion clinic.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Trainees also are on call to cover the UCSF needle stick hotline for 4-6 weeks during both years of training. Calls are taken from home at night and on weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
			   &lt;img width=&quot;280&quot; height=&quot;193&quot; class=&quot;imgRight&quot; src=&quot;/sites/giving.ucsf.edu/files/images/oem_pic1.jpg&quot;&gt;   &lt;h3&gt;The Following Provides Background on the Variety of Clinical Rotation Experiences Available to Residents&lt;/h3&gt;
			       &lt;p&gt;A minimum of four months must be devoted to clinical rotations in each of the two years of residency. The weekly continuity clinic contributes approximately one month of such clinical time; needlestick coverage contributes additional clinical time.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			 &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kaiser Permanente Medical Group — Occupational Medicine Clinic&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			General primary occupational medicine services with an emphasis on musculoskeletal evaluations and ergonomic issues. Location: Opera Plaza, San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;San Francisco Veterans Affairs Medical Center (SFVAMC)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			A variety of clinical experiences including general occupational medicine; compensation and pension determinations; post-traumatic stress disorder clinic; rehabilitation medicine; and environmental medicine (including Agent Orange and Gulf War Syndrome). Location: SFVAMC, San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UCSF Needlestick Hotline&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			First pager calls for the assessment and acute management of needle stick and related biohazard exposures among UCSF and UC Hospital employees under the directions of Drs. Robert Kosnik and Robert Harrison. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Multispecialty Rotation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			A month-long multispecialty rotation provides an opportunity to experiences half-day once weekly outpatient exposure to pulmonary, allergy, ophthalmology, neurology, ergonomics, dermatology, and complementary medicine at a number of different practice settings. Locations: UCSF Mt Zion, Kaiser San Francisco, UC Berkeley Tang Center, and an SF-based private practice setting.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lawrence Livermore National laboratory, Health Services Department (LLNL)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			LLNL is a Research and Development Laboratory with a focus on national security issues. The Health Services Department serves over 7000 employees and provides comprehensive clinical and consultative services, including medical surveillance, ergonomic, safety, and industrial hygiene evaluations, health promotion, employee assistance programs, and workers compensation management. LLNL has many interesting and unusual occupational health issues ranging from beryllium to biological agents and radiation. Rotation includes clinical service at their occupational clinic in addition to administrative activities. Location: Livermore.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pediatric Environmental Health Specialty Unit (PEHSU)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			This program is part of the OEM Division at SFGH, in partnership with the Northern California Poison Control Center and the UCSF Department of Pediatrics. The PEHSU responds to calls from clinicians and the public about pediatric environmental exposures, performs outreach and education to primary care pediatrics providers, and participates in the multidisciplinary clinic at Mount Zion when children or families with environmental exposures are evaluated. Location: San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			 &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;San Francisco Regional Poison Control Center (PCC)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Physician and pharmacologist teams advise physicians and the public regarding toxic ingestions (including medication adverse effects), and skin and inhalation exposures; consult on in-patient toxicology cases at San Francisco General Hospital; and provide telephone consultations on toxicology cases at other hospitals. Location: SFGH, San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;U.S. Healthworks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			U.S. Healthworks offers both urgent care walk in and pre-placement and surveillance services to employers which includes agricultural and other vulnerable workers. There are also several large industrial employers in the area. Location: Modesto, CA. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;WorkWell Medical Group&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Work Well Medical Group offers both urgent care walk in and pre-placement and surveillance services to employers in the Salinas Valley including a substantial segment of agricultural workers. These at risk populations provide a potentially unique opportunity for residents to address health care disparities in minority populations. Location: Salinas, CA.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;The Following Provides a Summary of Public Health Oriented Rotations&lt;/h3&gt;
			 &lt;p&gt;A minimum of two months of the practicum year must be devoted to public health rotations. Trainees may elect to spend two sequential months at one site, or may rotate through two different sites. Trainees interested in public health may spend additional elective months at any of these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC) &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			 The goal of this NGO is to preserve the environment and protect public health through education and advocacy. Areas of focus include diesel exhaust exposure reduction; reduction of greenhouse gases and conventional pollutants from stationary and mobile sources; reducing lead and mercury pollution; pesticide policy reform; drinking water regulation; and identification and elimination of endocrine disrupting chemicals in consumer products. Location: San Francisco
			 &lt;/p&gt;
			
			 &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;California Dept. of  Industrial Relations, Division of Workers Compensation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			 Trainees rotating at the California State Division of Workers Compensation will develop an understanding of the California workers’ compensation system and its role in the provision of care for ill and injured workers. Trainees will interact with a multidisciplinary team, including medical, legal, and other professionals, and will participate in a wide range of activities, including – but not limited to – internal, interdepartmental, and external stakeholder meetings, literature review, evaluating medical and claims data, and phone consultation and site visits as relevant. Location: Oakland, CA.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;California Department of Public Health — Occupational Health Branch (OHB) and Environmental Health Investigations Branch (EHIB)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The OHB identifies and evaluates workplace hazards, tracks patterns of work-related injury and illness, develops training and informational materials, provides technical assistance to prevent work-related injury and illness, and recommends protective occupational health standards. Programs include the: (1) Hazard Evaluation System and Information Service (HESIS) which evaluates hazards and provides information and technical assistance on new or unappreciated hazards; (2) Occupational Health Surveillance and Evaluation Program (OHSEP) which conducts research on work-related illness, injury and death in California; (3) Occupational Lead Poisoning Prevention Program (OLPPP) which provides information and assistance to identify lead hazards and prevent work-related lead poisoning; and (4) California Safe Cosmetics Program (CSCP) which collects and provides information on hazardous ingredients in cosmetic products sold in California. EHIB studies how the environment affects health and by educates and informs the public. EHIB units include: (1) Community Participation and Education Section; (2) Exposure Assessment Section; (3) Environmental Epidemiology Section; (4) Site Assessment Section. Location: Richmond, CA.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			 &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;California EPA — Office of Environmental Health Hazard Assessment (OEHHA)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			OEHHA is responsible for developing and providing risk managers in state and local
			government agencies with toxicological and medical information relevant to decisions involving public health. OEHHA’s responsibilities include: (1) Developing health-protective exposure standards for different media (air, water, land) to recommend to regulatory agencies, including ambient air quality standards for the Air Resources Board and drinking water chemical contaminant standards for the Department of Health Services; (2) Carrying out special investigations of potential environmental causes of illness, diseases and deaths; (3) Making recommendations with respect to sport and commercial fishing in areas where fish may be contaminated; (4) Assessing health risks to the public from air pollution, pesticide and other chemical contamination of food, seafood, drinking water, and consumer products; (5) Providing guidance to local agencies with specific public health problems, including appropriate actions to take in emergencies that may involve chemicals; (6) Implementing the provisions of the Safe Drinking Water and Toxic Enforcement Act of 1986 (Proposition 65). Location: Oakland, CA.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			 &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;California Department of Occupational Safety and Health (Cal/OSHA)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			State consultation and enforcement services for California OSHA regulations with offices throughout California. This rotation is often done in sequence with the Health Department rotation Location: Oakland, CA.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Labor Occupational Health Project (LOHP) UC Berkeley, Berkeley CA &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			LOHP is a community service program of the Center for Occupational and Environmental Health at the University of California, Berkeley. It works with unions, labor/management groups, community organizations, worker centers, small businesses, schools, academia, government agencies, and the general public addressing a variety of occupational health and safety issues. This rotation will include elements of policy, risk assessment and communication, and community outreach to at risk populations. Location: Berkeley&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;The Following are Various Corporate/Consulting/Administrative Rotation Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;
			 &lt;p&gt;A minimum of two months of the practicum year must be devoted to rotations in this category. Trainees interested in this type of practice may spend additional elective months at any of these sites.&lt;/p&gt;
			 &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Richard Cohen, MD&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			  Consultant to companies in biotechnology and pharmaceutical research and manufacturing, semiconductor equipment and microprocessor production, healthcare supplies and equipment manufacturing, and electronic equipment research and development. Location: South San Francisco, Peninsula, and North Bay areas.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Michael Fischman, MD, MPH&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Dr. Fischman is a consulting physician to semiconductor, chemical and photovoltaic panel manufacturing, and motion picture companies, and on medical/legal work in occupational toxicology at various sites in the Bay Area Rotations will provide exposure to a variety of settings and to a common model of corporate service for occupational health by private providers rather than full-time, in-house occupational health services. &lt;/p&gt;
			 &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Permanente Medical Group—Kaiser Permanente Northern California Administrative Offices &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			A non-clinical rotation that focuses on learning how Worker’s Compensation Utilization Review is performed, and how MPN networks are developed, managed and sold from inside a large HMO. Location: Oakland, CA.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jordan Rinker, MD, MPH &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Consulting Medical Director to pharmaceutical research and manufacturing, biotechnology, medical center occupational health groups. Location: Various sites in Bay Area.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thomas Allems, MD MPH&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Dr. Allems is a private practice occupational medicine consultant who provides experience in medical-legal assessments an related reporting. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Research Project &lt;/h3&gt;
			 &lt;p&gt;Projects typically span most of the course of the year with a full-time block for in-depth work. A research mentor is selected before the start of the second year. It is expected that research results will be submitted for peer review as an abstract for a presentation at an occupational or environmental health conference and residents are encouraged to develop a manuscript for publication in a scientific journal. The full-time research month(s) should be completed in time to ensure that the project can be completed before the end of training. Training in clinical research methods is provided through a summer workshop. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			 &lt;p&gt;Examples of research projects carried out by residents in recent years include:&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apatira, L.&lt;/strong&gt; “Physical Inactivity and the Workplace: Using Conceptual Models to Examine Occupational and Personal Risk Factors.”
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Berenji, M.&lt;/strong&gt; “Occupational Cancer Risk Among Firefighters.”
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dinenberg, E.&lt;/strong&gt; “Social Support and Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder.”
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kaitz, M.&lt;/strong&gt; “Hazard Analysis of Consumer Product Chemicals in U.S. Indoor Dust.”
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khafagy, A.&lt;/strong&gt; “High-altitude Alpine Therapy and Lung Function in Asthma: Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.”
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lin, K.&lt;/strong&gt; “Reviewing Acute Cardiopulmonary Effects from Wood Smoke Exposure in Controlled Exposure Studies.”
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MacIsaac, J.&lt;/strong&gt; “Triclosan Exposure in Healthcare Workers.”
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;McLaughlin, E.&lt;/strong&gt;  “Anaphylaxis Following a Laboratory Mouse Bite.”
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Murphy, C.&lt;/strong&gt; “Planning for Long Duration Space Flights: Validation of Model Predictions of Alertness, Performance, and Sleepiness.”
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Petersen, Scott.&lt;/strong&gt;  “Chromium 6 and Stomach Cancer: a Meta-Analysis.”
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Puri, R.&lt;/strong&gt; “Occupational Radiation Exposure and Breast Cancer: Case Report of a Dental Worker.”
			 &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
			
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
26faq
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Occupational  and Environmental Medicine?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			Occupational and Environmental Medicine (OEM) is a sub-specialty of the American Board of Preventive Medicine. OEM focuses on ways that workplace, home, or community environmental factors affect human health. Our field spans workplace safety; infectious disease hazards in the workplace or community; the toxic effects of chemicals (in the workplace, food, water, air, soil, or consumer products); effects of physical agents (such as noise or radiation) on health; chronic musculoskeletal stressors and ergonomic issues; workplace stress and other psychological issues; and even global environmental health issues (such as the effects of climate change on health). OEM is an exciting field because there are many opportunities for research and intervention to help improve the health of individuals and communities. &lt;/p&gt;
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does  postgraduate training at UCSF in Occupational and Environmental Medicine (OEM) offer  ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			          Our ACGME-accredited program was established in 1977 and is one of the top OEM training programs in the country. We specialize in training physicians for leadership positions in academic research, teaching, public health, and policy positions, as well as providing training in clinical OEM. Our trainees build a foundation of knowledge in epidemiology, toxicology, biostatistics, risk assessment and public health through participation in the master's program at UC Berkeley's School of Public Health. Trainees then develop more in-depth expertise through industry and community site-visits, research projects, complex clinical evaluations, and presentations. Board certification in Preventive Medicine – OEM opens up many career opportunities to physicians in academia, clinical settings, industry, consulting, and government.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the  components of OEM training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			        OEM training is a two-year program. The first year typically focuses on coursework toward a master’s in Public Health (MPH) from UC Berkeley. The second year consists primarily of month-long rotations at a variety of clinical, research, and public health sites. Physicians who already have an MPH degree complete two years of rotations, although additional coursework may be needed to meet requirements; eligibility for matriculation into the second year depends on prior completion of another primary board as well as a prior MPH or equivalent. Additional components of the UCSF training program include an in-depth research project, site visits to workplaces and communities, Grand Rounds, research seminars, case conferences, journal clubs, and other learning opportunities such as local and national professional meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How many residents or  fellows do you have in your program?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			         We are accredited for a maximum of eight trainees across the two years of the program. However, our ability to accommodate trainees may be limited by available funding. In the current year and previous year we have had a full complement of 8 trainees, This has included active service military trainees from the Navy and Air Force.  &lt;/p&gt;
			
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the  prerequisites for your program?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			        Physicians who have undergone a minimum of one year of postgraduate training in an ACGME-approved program are eligible for consideration for our training program. We give strong preference to applicants who have completed a residency program (in Internal Medicine, Emergency Medicine, Family Practice, General Preventive Medicine or other specialty). We also look for applicants with a demonstrated commitment to OEM through experience in clinical, research, policy, or public health practice.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can foreign medical  graduates apply to the program?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			        Foreign graduates are welcome to apply to the program. However, all of our trainees must have a California medical license or training authorization and foreign medical graduates are not eligible until they have completed 24 months of training in the US. In addition, all foreign medical graduates must have passed the USMLE examination and hold valid ECFMG certificates as well as either a valid J-1 visa, or permanent US residency status or citizenship. If you meet the above criteria, we will consider your application. Unfortunately, we are unable to provide stipends or funding support trainees who are not US citizens or residents and thus external support from another source is required.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			      &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What financial  support and benefits does the program offer?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			          OEM trainees who are US citizens or residents are eligible to receive a monthly stipend, in accordance with UCSF Graduate Medical Education policies. Health insurance is provided for the trainee and eligible dependents. For more information on support and benefits, please refer to &lt;a href=&quot;http://medschool2.ucsf.edu/gme/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;medschool2.ucsf.edu/gme/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://medschool.ucsf.edu/gme&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is your calendar for applications and training?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			        We accept applications via ERAS from September 15 – November 6  (last interview date if invited, November 20) for the training program starting the following July 1.&lt;/p&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
27salary
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			
			
			
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;
			UCSF provides a competitive package of salary and health benefits to its postgraduate trainees. In 2017-18, the annual salary for entering trainees at the PGY2 level is $57,408 and PGY4 level is $62,018, with an additional $1,008.33/month in housing allowance for all residents. Other benefits include:
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Health insurance for the trainee, their spouse/domestic partner, and eligible dependents;
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dental and vision plans;
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Life insurance, accidental death and dismemberment, and long-term disability insurance;
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Full access to the UCSF Library and its electronic resources;
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Financial support for attending conferences and other events.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
			More information about the health benefits package, diversity programs and living in the Bay Area is available at:
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://medschool2.ucsf.edu/gme&quot;&gt;Graduate Medical Education site&lt;/a&gt;.
			
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
28allfaculty
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Faculty of the Division of Occupational and Environmental Medicine provide services in the UCSF Medical Center at Mt. Zion Occupational Medicine Faculty Practice and Multidisciplinary Clinic, at Kaiser Permanente, and at the Northern California Poison Control Center. &lt;p/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our faculty has affiliations with pulmonary medicine, orthopedic surgery, toxicology, dermatology, industrial hygiene, bioengineering and occupational health nursing. Close ties are maintained with the California Department of Public Health, the California Environmental Protection Agency, the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, and the World Health Organization.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Core Occupational Medicine Faculty&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:20px;&quot;&gt;	
			
			&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=7d0449bf99a9c76c579c8a50e83319a1&amp;name=BALMES%2CJOHN+R&quot;&gt;John Balmes, MD &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;	
			&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=a6343c52cbcf26e9bbe9b6e2b21e54d7&amp;name=BLANC%2CPAUL+D&quot;&gt;Paul Blanc, MD, MSPH &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;	
			&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=ed038116f2d49334af7f9be1a5c2354a&amp;name=HARRISON%2CROBERT+J&quot;&gt;Robert Harrison, MD, MPH &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;	
			&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=1084b1f89c5201f616e032d27f38fe1b&amp;name=KOSNIK%2CROBERT+EDWARD&quot;&gt;Robert Kosnik, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;	
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://clinpharm.ucsf.edu/people/kolson.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kent R. Olson, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;	
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/ProfileDetails.aspx?From=SE&amp;Person=5247275&quot; target=_&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Patricia Quinlan, MPH, CIH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;	
			&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=75e7e2cfbfb20c3de3f29e025732b033&amp;name=REMPEL%2CDAVID+M&quot;&gt;David Rempel, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;	
			&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=e1202873a16c967b69b4d6e670b69ecf&amp;name=ROISMAN%2CRACHEL+E&quot;&gt;Rachel Roisman, MD, MPH &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://sph.berkeley.edu/faculty/seward.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;James Seward, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Supporting UC Clinical Faculty and Other Occupational Medicine Preceptors&lt;/h3&gt;	
			&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:20px;&quot;&gt;Tom Allems, MD, MPH &lt;br /&gt;
			Richard Cohen, MD&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drcraner.com/education_credentials.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;James Craner, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ehib.org/person.jsp?person_key=3502&amp;eo&quot; target=_&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Rupali Das, MD, MPH &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fischmanmed.com/?page_id=20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Michael Fischman, MD, MPH &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Robert Goldberg, MD &lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://switchboard.nrdc.org/blogs/sjanssen/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sarah Janssen, MD, PhD, MPH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.permanente.net/homepage/kaiser/doctor/pauljohnson/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Paul Johnson, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.permanente.net/homepage/kaiser/doctor/romankownacki/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Roman Kownacki, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Yannick Leguyader, MD&lt;br /&gt;
			Peter Lichty, MD&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/meister.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ray Meister, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Mark Miller, MD&lt;br /&gt;
			Linda Morse, MD&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/rinker.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jordan Rinker, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanrutchik.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jonathan Rutchik, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Erika Schwilk, MD, MPH &lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;/about/faculty.html?key=367673d6f89328cdde864c868ecd64fd&amp;name=SHUSTERMAN%2CDENNIS+J&quot;&gt;Dennis Shusterman, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;	
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.calepa.ca.gov/about/Bios/Solomon.htm&quot;&gt;Gina M. Solomon, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://sph.berkeley.edu/faculty/steinmaus.php&quot;&gt;Craig Steinmaus, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;	
			Susan Tierman, MD&lt;br /&gt;
			Christina Wang, MD, MPH&lt;br /&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Faculty from Related Disciplines&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/faculty/barbara-burgel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Barbara J. Burgel, RN, PhD, COHN-S, FAAN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/faculty/oisaeng-hong&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Oisaeng Hong, RN, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/faculty/soo-jeong-lee&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Soo Jeong Lee, RN, PhD&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;
			
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/faculty/dana-drew-nord&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dana Drew-Nord, RN, PhD&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
29faculty
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
30index
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Faculty of the Division of Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine provide services at: the Mount Zion Occupational Medicine Faculty Practice and Multidisciplinary Clinic; Kaiser Permanente; the San Francisco Division of the California Poison Control System; San Francisco General Hospital (SFGH) Employee Health; and the San Francisco Veteran Affairs Medical Center (SFVAMC).   &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;div style=&quot;float:right;width:350px;&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;../images/oemfaculty.jpg&quot; style=&quot;max-width:350px;&quot; class=&quot;image&quot;&gt;
			&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot; style=&quot;width:360px;&quot;&gt;Faculty on Industrial Site Visit&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our faculty members have affiliations with pulmonary medicine, toxicology, industrial hygiene, bioengineering and occupational health nursing. Close ties are maintained with the California Department of Public Health, California Environmental Protection Agency, and National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;The OEM residency program is led by   &lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=a6343c52cbcf26e9bbe9b6e2b21e54d7&amp;amp;name=BLANC%2CPAUL+D&quot;&gt;Paul D. Blanc, MD, MSPH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=ed038116f2d49334af7f9be1a5c2354a&amp;amp;name=HARRISON%2CROBERT+J&quot;&gt;Robert Harrison, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;br&gt;
			&lt;h3&gt;Core Occupational Medicine Faculty&lt;/h3&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=7d0449bf99a9c76c579c8a50e83319a1&amp;amp;name=BALMES%2CJOHN+R&quot;&gt;John Balmes, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Director, &lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;COEH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Health effects of ozone, nitrogen dioxide and particulate matter. Research projects include controlled exposure chamber studies on human subjects, epidemiologic studies on air quality and asthma in Fresno, and exposures to indoor smoke from cook stoves and health effects in Guatemala and Malawi.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=20724548&amp;name=BLANC%2C+PAUL+D&quot;&gt;Paul Blanc, MD, MSPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Chief, Division of OEM: Parnassus-Mt Zion, SFGH, and VAMC&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Asthma and COPD in relation to workplace and environmental factors; occupational and environmental toxicology with a focus on pulmonary responses; the history of occupational and environmental medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/samuel.goldman&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Samuel Goldman, MD MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Adjunct Associate Professor, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Environmental Medicine Clinic, SFVAMC Parkinson’s Disease Research, Education and Clinical Center, SFVAMC&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Occupational and environmental epidemiology of Parkinson’s and other neurodegenerative diseases.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/sandeep.guntur&quot;  target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sandeep Guntur, MD MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Chief for Compensation and Pension, San Francisco VAMC &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/carisa.harris-adamson&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Carisa Harris-Adamson, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Director, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ergo.berkeley.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ergonomics Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;, UC Berkeley/UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Research Interests: Occupational ergonomics; peripheral nerve entrapment, work-related tendon disorders; cardiovascular load; workplace intervention studies.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=ed038116f2d49334af7f9be1a5c2354a&amp;amp;name=HARRISON%2CROBERT+J&quot;&gt;Robert Harrison, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;(Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Occupational Medicine Clinic, UCSF Mount Zion&lt;br /&gt;
			  Public Health Medical Officer, California Department of Public Health&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Risk factors and prevention strategies for work-related carpal tunnel syndrome, heat stress, asthma and pesticide poisoning in the California workforce; risk factors and prevention strategies for work-related fatalities.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=1084b1f89c5201f616e032d27f38fe1b&amp;amp;name=KOSNIK%2CROBERT+EDWARD&quot;&gt;Robert Kosnik, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			  Clinical Professor Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Chief Occupational Health Services, UCSF &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/mehrdad.arjomandi&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mehrdad Arjomandi, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Director, Human Exposure Laboratory SFGH&lt;br /&gt;
			Environmental Medicine Clinic, SFVAMC  &lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Exposure-related lung diseases; air pollution contribution to development and progression of respiratory (asthma and COPD) and cardiovascular (atherosclerosis) diseases; ozone inhalational challenge as a model of respiratory disease exacerbation.    &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=26779686&amp;name=QUINLAN%2CPATRICIA+J&quot;&gt;Patricia Quinlan, MPH, CIH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Industrial Hygienist (Retired), UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Occupational and Environmental exposure assessment for studies of asthma, COPD, Parkinson's disease, and childhood leukemia.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=26916759&amp;name=REMPEL%2C+DAVID+M&quot;&gt;David Rempel, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Professor of Medicine, UCSF	&lt;br /&gt;
			Former Director, Retired &lt;a href=&quot;http://ergo.berkeley.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ergonomics Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;, UC Berkeley/UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Occupational ergonomics; peripheral nerve entrapment, work-related tendon disorders; hand biomechanics, tool design, workplace intervention studies.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/suzaynn.schick&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Suzaynn Schick, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Adjunct Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Director, Human Exposure Laboratory, ZSFG&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Secondhand and “thirdhand” cigarette smoke exposure effects; e-cigarette exposure; wood smoke health effects.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sph.berkeley.edu/faculty/seward.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;James Seward, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			(Retired) Director, Health Services, Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory&lt;br /&gt;
			Chair, OEM Residency Advisory Committee&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Ionizing radiation health effects; health promotion in the workplace; management of occupational health programs.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=367673d6f89328cdde864c868ecd64fd&amp;amp;name=SHUSTERMAN%2CDENNIS+J&quot;&gt;Dennis Shusterman, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Professor Emeritus of Clinical Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Health effects of irritant air pollutants on the upper airway, including the nose, paranasal sinuses, and vocal cords. The effects of sidestream tobacco smoke on the upper airway. Please see  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noselab.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;NoseLab&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sph.berkeley.edu/faculty/steinmaus.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Craig Steinmaus, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Adjunct Professor of Epidemiology, UC Berkeley&lt;br /&gt;
			Office of Environmental Health Hazard Assessment, Cal/EPA&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Health effects of drinking water contaminants such as arsenic and perchlorate. Meta-analysis and epidemiologic methods.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Supporting UC Clinical Faculty and Other Occupational Medicine Preceptors&lt;/h3&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tom Allems, MD, MPH&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Consultant &amp;mdash; Occupational Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Richard Cohen MD MPH &lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Private Practice &amp;mdash; Occupational Medicine and Industrial Toxicology&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests and Practice Focus:&lt;/i&gt; Exposure assessment, development of occupational exposure limits, corporate global medical director, medical surveillance and biologic monitoring, pharmaceutical industry occupational exposure containment, and litigation consultation and testimony.
			
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drcraner.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;James Craner, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Consultant/Clinician—Occupational and Environmental Medicine, Reno &amp; Las Vegas, NV / Sacramento, CA&lt;br /&gt;
			President, Verdi Technology, Inc. (webOSCAR&amp;trade;)&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Medical surveillance and biological monitoring; lithium ion battery manufacturing; audiometric data analytics; health and safety compliance &amp; software; cyanide antidotes.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/rupali.das-melnyk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rupali Das, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Senior Vice President and California Medical Director, Zenith Insurance &lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Early intervention following work-related illness or injury to mitigate the negative impact of chronic comorbidities and psychosocial factors on recovery; promoting safer alternatives to chemicals used in the home and workplace; tracking work-related illness to understand etiology and recommend preventive measures; measuring human exposures to chemicals though biomonitoring to reduce health effects and promote safer and more responsible chemical use policies.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://profiles.ucsf.edu/timur.durrani&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Timur Durrani, MD, MPH MBA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Director, Occupational Health, Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests&lt;/i&gt;: Occupational and environmental toxicology and emergency preparedness&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fischmanmed.com/?page_id=20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Michael Fischman, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Medical Director, Intel Corporation&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Robert Goldberg, MD&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=20392387&amp;name=JANSSEN%2CSARAH+J.&quot;&gt;Sarah Janssen, MD, PhD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Urology and Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Staff Physician - Kaiser Permanente Medical Group San Francisco&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Environmental exposures to endocrine disrupting chemicals such as phthalates, bisphenol A, and flame retardants; chemical screening and testing strategies for carcinogens and endocrine disruptors.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.permanente.net/homepage/kaiser/doctor/pauljohnson/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Paul Johnson, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Kaiser Permanente Medical Group San Francisco
				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.permanente.net/homepage/kaiser/doctor/romankownacki/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Roman Kownacki, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Medical Director, Regional Occupational Health, Kaiser Permanente&lt;br /&gt;
			Chief, Occupational Medicine Northern California, Kaiser Permanente&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/meister.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ray Meister, MD, MPH &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			California Division of Workers Compensation&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/ucpehsu/OurTeam/Miller.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mark Miller, MD &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Pediatrics)&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Director, Pediatric Environmental Health Specialty Unit&lt;br /&gt;
			Air Toxicology and Epidemiology Section, OEHHA, Cal/EPA&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; The unique susceptibility of children to environmental chemicals, particularly the impact of early life exposures on neurological and pulmonary development and associated signaling events. Recent chemicals of interest include perchlorate, secondhand smoke, and lindane. Translating new epidemiologic and toxicologic findings relevant to pediatric environmental health to the clinical audience.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Linda Morse, MD &lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Proctor, Kaiser SF Occupational Health&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Staff, Premier Comp Medical Group&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/people/faculty/rinker.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jordan Rinker, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Private Consultant &amp;mdash; Occupational Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanrutchik.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jonathan Rutchik, MD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Private Practice &amp;mdash; Neurology and Occupational Medicine&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uhs.berkeley.edu/students/medical/medicalstaff.shtml&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Erika Schwilk, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Staff Physician, Tang Center at UC Berkeley&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.calepa.ca.gov/about/Bios/Solomon.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gina M. Solomon, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Occupational Medicine)&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Deputy Secretary for Science and Health, California Environmental  Protection Agency (Cal/EPA)&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;i&gt;Research Interests:&lt;/i&gt; Health effects associated with climate change, including heat waves, infectious disease shifts, and disaster response post-Katrina; public health strategies for preparing for climate change; environmental exposure assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mydoctor.kaiserpermanente.org/ncal/provider/christinawang&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Christina Wang, MD, MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Clinical Professor of Medicine, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Staff Physician, Kaiser Permanente Medical Group, San Francisco&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Faculty from the Occupational Health Nursing Program&lt;/h3&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=21098355&amp;name=BURGEL%2C+BARBARA+J&quot;&gt;Barbara Burgel, PhD, RN, MS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;(Department of Community Health Systems)&lt;br /&gt;
			Clinical Professor of Nursing (Retired), UCSF&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/faculty/oisaeng-hong&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Oisaeng Hong, RN, PhD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (Department of Community Health Systems)&lt;br /&gt;
			Professor of Nursing, UCSF&lt;br /&gt;
			Director, Occupational Health Nursing Program, UCSF&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/faculty/faculty.html?key=29858255&amp;name=LEE%2C+SOO-JEONG&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Soo Jeong Lee, RN, PhD, ANP&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Department of Community Health Systems)&lt;br /&gt;
			Assistant Professor, UCSF School of Nursing&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nursing.ucsf.edu/faculty/dana-drew-nord&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dana Drew-Nord, RN, PhD&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Associate Clinical Professor, UCSF School of Nursing &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
31search
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
32index
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Current areas of research include:&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Development of worsened impairment, disability, and deficits in quality of life with COPD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21124233&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The role of physical  inactivity in increasing disability among older adults with obstructive airway  disease.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Katz P, Chen H, Omachi TA, Gregorich SE, Julian L, Cisternas  M, Balmes J, Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2011 May-Jun;31(3):193-7.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19952768&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Disability in valued life  activities among individuals with COPD and other respiratory conditions.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Katz PP, Gregorich S, Eisner M, Julian L, Chen H, Yelin E,  Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			  J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev. 2010 Mar-Apr;30(2):126-36.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22890622&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lower health literacy is  associated with poorer health status and outcomes in chronic obstructive  pulmonary disease.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Omachi TA, Sarkar U, Yelin EH, Blanc PD, Katz PP.&lt;br /&gt;
			  J Gen Intern Med. 2013 Jan;28(1):74-81. Epub 2012 Aug 14.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26683222&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Obesity and functioning among individuals with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD).&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Katz P, Iribarren C, Sanchez G, Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			COPD (J Chronic Obst Pulm Dis) 2016;13:352-9.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health outcomes  over a range of asthma severity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21277512&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Evaluating quality of  life in patients with asthma and rhinitis: English adaptation of the rhinasthma  questionnaire.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Chen H, Cisternas MG, Katz PP, Omachi TA, Trupin L, Yelin  EH, Balmes JR, Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2011 Feb;106(2):110-118.e1. Epub 2011 Jan 8.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18727467&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Risk factors for death in  adults with severe asthma.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Omachi TA, Iribarren C, Sarkar U, Tolstykh I, Yelin EH, Katz  PP, Blanc PD, Eisner MD.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2008 Aug;101(2):130-6. &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact of environmental exposures, including secondhand smoke exposure and air pollution, on patients with obstructive lung disease&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19152968&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Exposure to traffic: lung  function and health status in adults with asthma.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Balmes JR, Earnest G, Katz PP, Yelin EH, Eisner MD, Chen H,  Trupin L, Lurmann F, Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2009 Mar;123(3):626-31. Epub 2009 Jan 18.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16756671&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Directly measured  secondhand smoke exposure and COPD health outcomes.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Eisner MD, Balmes J, Yelin EH, Katz PP, Hammond SK, Benowitz  N, Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			  BMC Pulm Med. 2006 Jun 6;6:12.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23237178&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mediators of the  socioeconomic gradient in outcomes of adult asthma and rhinitis.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Trupin L, Katz PP, Balmes JR, Chen H, Yelin EH, Omachi T,  Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Am J Public Health. 2013 Feb;103(2):e31-8. Epub 2012 Dec 13.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21824866&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fungal chitin from  asthma-associated home environments induces eosinophilic lung infiltration.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Van Dyken SJ, Garcia D, Porter P, Huang X, Quinlan PJ, Blanc  PD, Corry DB, Locksley RM.&lt;br /&gt;
			  J Immunol. 2011 Sep 1;187(5):2261-7. Epub 2011 Aug 8.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24528996&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Annual average ambient particulate matter exposure estimates, measured home particulate matter, and hair nicotine are associated with respiratory outcomes in adults with asthma&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			Balmes JR, Cisternas M, Quinlan PJ, Trupin L, Lurmann FW; Katz PP, Blanc PD. &lt;br /&gt;
			Environ Res 2014; Feb 129: 1-10.  &lt;/p&gt;
			
			  
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24792855&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Outdoor air pollution and asthma&lt;/a&gt;.
			&lt;br /&gt;Guarnieri M, Balmes JR.
			&lt;br /&gt;Lancet. 2014 May 3;383(9928):1581-92&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24400619&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Climate change. A global threat to cardiopulmonary health&lt;/a&gt;.
			&lt;br /&gt;Rice MB, Thurston GD, Balmes JR, Pinkerton KE.
			&lt;br /&gt;Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2014 Mar 1;189:512-9&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Healthcare costs of lung disease&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12789219&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A comprehensive study of  the direct and indirect costs of adult asthma.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Cisternas MG, Blanc PD, Yen IH, Katz PP, Earnest G, Eisner  MD, Shiboski S, Yelin EH.&lt;br /&gt;
			  J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2003 Jun;111(6):1212-8.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23703646&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Risk adjustment for health care financing in chronic disease:  What are we missing by failing to account for disease severity?&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;br /&gt;Omachi TA, Gregorich SE, Eisner MD, Penaloza RA, Tolstykh IV, Yelin EH, Iribarren C, Dudley RA, Blanc PD.
			&lt;br /&gt;Medical Care 2013;51:740-7.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effect of occupational exposures on health outcomes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/12598220&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;American Thoracic Society  Statement: Occupational contribution to the burden of airway disease.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Balmes J, Becklake M, Blanc P, Henneberger P, Kreiss K, Mapp  C, Milton D, Schwartz D, Toren K, Viegi G; Environmental and Occupational  Health Assembly, American Thoracic Society.&lt;br /&gt;
			Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2003 Mar 1;167(5):787-97.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19528835&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Further exploration of  the links between occupational exposure and chronic obstructive pulmonary  disease.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Blanc PD, Eisner MD, Earnest G, Trupin L, Balmes JR, Yelin  EH, Gregorich SE, Katz PP.&lt;br /&gt;
			  J Occup Environ Med. 2009 Jul;51(7):804-10. &lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22744883&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chronic obstructive  pulmonary disease among residents of an historically industrialised area.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Darby AC, Waterhouse JC, Stevens V, Billings CG, Billings  CG, Burton CM, Young C, Wight J, Blanc PD, Fishwick D.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Thorax. 2012 Oct;67(10):901-7. Epub 2012 Jun 28.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23547628&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;COPD causation and workplace exposures: an assessment of agreement among expert clinical raters&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
			Fishwick D, Darby A, Hnizdo E, Barber C, Sumner J, Barraclough R, Bolton C, Burge S, Calverley P, Hopkinson N, Hoyle J, Lawson R, Niven R, Pickering T, Prowse K, Reid P, Warburton C, Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			COPD (J Chronic Obst Pulm Dis) 2013; 10: 172-179.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24673105&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gender differences in work-related asthma: surveillance data from California, Massachusetts, Michigan, and New Jersey, 1993-2008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			White GE, Seaman C, Filios MS, Mazurek JM, Flattery J, Harrison RJ, Reilly MJ, Rosenman KD, Lumia ME, Stephens AC, Pechter E, Fitzsimmons K, Davis LK.&lt;br /&gt;
			J Asthma. 2014 Sep;51(7):691-702&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26351141&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Isocyanates and work-related asthma: Findings from California, Massachusetts, Michigan, and New Jersey, 1993-2008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			Lefkowitz D, Pechter E, Fitzsimmons K, Lumia M, Stephens AC, Davis L, Flattery J, Weinberg J, Harrison RJ, Reilly MJ, Filios MS, White GE, Rosenman KD.&lt;br /&gt;
			Am J Ind Med. 2015 Nov;58(11):1138-49
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact of obstructive lung diseases on work disability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21047868&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Development of disability  in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: beyond lung function.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Eisner MD, Iribarren C, Blanc PD, Yelin EH, Ackerson L, Byl  N, Omachi TA, Sidney S, Katz PP.&lt;br /&gt;
			Thorax. 2011 Feb;66(2):108-14. Epub 2010 Nov 3.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19158120&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;An international  prospective general population-based study of respiratory work disability.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Torén K, Zock JP, Kogevinas M, Plana E, Sunyer J, Radon K,  Jarvis D, Kromhout H, d'Errico A, Payo F, Antó JM, Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Thorax. 2009 Apr;64(4):339-44. Epub 2009 Jan 21.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			  
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23450785&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Predictors of respiratory sickness absence: an international population-based study&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt; 
			Kim J-L, Blanc PD, Villani S, Oliveri M, Urrutia I, van Sprundel M, Storaas T, Le Moual N, Zock J-P, Torén K.&lt;br /&gt;
			Am J Ind Med 2013; 56:541-49.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biomarkers linked to adverse respiratory disease outcomes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21429222&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Matrix  metalloproteinase-9 predicts pulmonary status declines in α1-antitrypsin  deficiency.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Omachi TA, Eisner MD, Rames A, Markovtsova L, Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Respir Res. 2011 Mar 23;12:35. &lt;/p&gt;
			  
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23461078&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chest wall shrapnel-induced beryllium-sensitization and associated pulmonary disease&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			Fireman E, Bar Shai A, Lerman Y, Topilsky M, Blanc PD, Maier L, Li L, Chandra S, Abraham JM, Fomin I, Aviram G, Abraham JL.&lt;br /&gt;
			Sarcoidosis Vasc Diffuse Lung Dis Sarcoidosis Vasc Diffuse Lung Dis 2012; 29: 147-150.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23467606&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adverse respiratory effects associated with cadmium exposure in small-scale jewellery workshops in India&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
			Moitra S, Blanc PD, Sahu S.&lt;br /&gt;
			Thorax 2013; 68:565-70.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23716171&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thirdhand cigarette smoke in an experimental chamber: evidence of surface deposition of nicotine, nitrosamines and polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons and de novo formation of NNK&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			Schick SF, Farraro KF, Perrino C, Sleiman M, van de Vossenberg G, Trinh MP, Hammond SK, Jenkins BM, Balmes J.&lt;br /&gt;
			Tob Control. 2014 Mar;23(2):152-9&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Novel or Emerging Exposure Scenarios  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24270292&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Five-year function observations and associations with a smoking ban among healthy miners at high altitude (4000 m)&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
			Vinnikov D, Blanc PD, Brimkulov N, Redding-Jones R.&lt;br /&gt;
			J Occup Environ Med 2013; 55:1422-5.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23450690&quot;&gt;Fatalities due to dichloromethane in paint strippers: a continuing problem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			Macisaac J, Harrison R, Krishnaswami J, McNary J, Suchard J, Boysen-Osborn M, Cierpich H, Styles L, Shusterman D.&lt;br /&gt;
			Am J Ind Med. 2013 Aug;56(8):907-10&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25189564&quot;&gt;Airflow obstruction among street vendors refilling cigarette lighter with liquefied petroleum gas. Int J&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Moitra S, Blanc PD, Brashier BB.&lt;br /&gt;
			Int J Tuberc Lung Dis 2014; 18:1126-31&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25099409&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Healthcare worker exposures to the antibacterial agent triclosan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			MacIsaac JK, Gerona R, Blanc PD, Apatira L, Friesen M, Coppolino M, Janssen S.&lt;br /&gt;
			J Occup Environ Med 2014; 56:834-39.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0088455&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Effects of woodsmoke exposure on airway inflammation in rural Guatemalan women&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			Guarnieri MJ, Diaz JV, Basu C, Diaz A, Pope D, Smith KR, Smith-Sivertsen T, Bruce N, Solomon C, McCracken J, Balmes JR.&lt;br /&gt;
			PLoS One. 2014 Mar 13;9(3):e88455&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26484688&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Coccidioidomycosis among Workers Constructing Solar Power Farms, California, USA, 2011-2014.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Wilken JA, Sondermeyer G, Shusterman D, McNary J, Vugia DJ, McDowell A, Borenstein P, Gilliss D, Ancock B, Prudhomme J, Gold D, Windham GC, Lee L, Materna BL. &lt;br /&gt;
			Emerg Infect Dis 2015; 21(11):1997-2005.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25412059&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			Lung transplantation for hypersensitivity pneumonitis.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Kern R, Singer J, Koth Laura, Mooney J, Golden J, Hays S, Greenland J, Wolters P, Ghio E, Jones K, Leard L, Kukreja J, Blanc P.&lt;br /&gt;
			Chest 2015; 147:1558-1561.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27730148&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fungal contamination of the respiratory tract and associated respiratory impairment among saw-mill workers in India. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Adhikari A, Sahu S, Bandyopadhyay A, Blanc PD, Moitra S.&lt;br /&gt;
			ERJ Open Research Oct 2015; 1(2) &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26866344&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Occupational HIV Transmission Among Male Adult Film Performers - Multiple States, 2014.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Wilken JA, Ried C, Rickett P, Arno JN, Mendez Y, Harrison RJ, Wohlfeiler D, Bauer HM, Joyce MP, Switzer WM, Heneine W, Shankar A, Mark KE&lt;br /&gt;
			MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2016 Feb 12;65(5):110-4.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26766558&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sudden Deaths Among Oil and Gas Extraction Workers Resulting from Oxygen Deficiency and Inhalation of Hydrocarbon Gases and Vapors - United States, January 2010-March 2015.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Harrison RJ, Retzer K, Kosnett MJ, Hodgson M, Jordan T, Ridl S, Kiefer M.&lt;br /&gt;
			MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2016 Jan 15;65(1):6-9. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26419295&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Is smoking a predictor for acute mountain sickness? Findings from a meta-analysis.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Vinnikov D, Blanc PD, Steinmaus C.&lt;br /&gt;
			Nicotine Tob Res; 2016, 18:1509-1516.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			
			
			
			
			
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcomes, quality of life, and disability in obstructive sleep apnea, in particular overlap with COPD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19544756&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Obstructive sleep apnea:  a risk factor for work disability.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Omachi TA, Claman DM, Blanc PD, Eisner MD.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Sleep. 2009 Jun;32(6):791-8.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22429651&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Disturbed sleep among  COPD patients is longitudinally associated with mortality and adverse COPD  outcomes.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Omachi TA, Blanc PD, Claman DM, Chen H, Yelin EH, Julian L,  Katz PP.&lt;br /&gt;
			Sleep Med. 2012 May;13(5):476-83. Epub 2012 Mar 18.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respiratory and non-respiratory factors in quality of life changes following lung transplantation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22071439&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Survival following lung  transplantation for silicosis and other occupational lung diseases.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Singer JP, Chen H, Phelan T, Kukreja J, Golden JA, Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Occup Med (Lond). 2012 Mar;62(2):134-7. Epub 2011 Nov 9.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			  
			   &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24355825&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Development and validation of a lung transplant-specific disability questionnaire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt; 
			Singer JP Blanc PD, Dean M, Hays S, Leard L, Kukreja J, Golden J, Katz PP.&lt;br /&gt;
			Thorax 2014; 69:445-50.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26258797 target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Frailty phenotypes, disability, and outcomes in adult candidates for lung transplantation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Singer JP, Diamond JM, Gries CJ, McDonnough J, Blanc PD, et. al. &lt;br /&gt;
			Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2015; 192: 1325-1334.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality of life and patient perceived health status and medication effects in pulmonary hypertension&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21273391&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Comparison of cardiac and  pulmonary-specific quality-of-life measures in pulmonary arterial hypertension.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Chen H, De Marco T, Kobashigawa EA, Katz PP, Chang VW, Blanc  PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			Eur Respir J. 2011 Sep;38(3):608-16. Epub 2011 Jan 27.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22490871&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Effects of commercial air  travel on patients with pulmonary hypertension air travel and pulmonary  hypertension.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Roubinian N, Elliott CG, Barnett CF, Blanc PD, Chen J, De  Marco T, Chen H.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Chest. 2012 Oct;142(4):885-92.&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Occupational and environmental disorders of the upper airway&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19807979&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nasal physiological  reactivity of subjects with nonallergic rhinitis to cold air provocation: a  pilot comparison of subgroups.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Shusterman DJ, Tilles SA.&lt;br /&gt;
			Am J Rhinol Allergy. 2009 Sep-Oct;23(5):475-9. &lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22487289&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pilot evaluation of the  nasal nitric oxide response to humming as an index of osteomeatal patency.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Shusterman DJ, Weaver EM, Goldberg AN, Schick SF, Wong HH,  Balmes JR.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Am J Rhinol Allergy. 2012 Mar-Apr;26(2):123-6.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23153606&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Occupational rhinitis and  other work-related upper respiratory tract conditions.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Zhao YA, Shusterman D.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Clin Chest Med. 2012 Dec;33(4):637-47.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23859154&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thirty minute-exposure to aged cigarette smoke increases nasal congestion in nonsmokers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			Schick SF, van den Vossenberg G, Luo A, Whitlatch A, Jacob P 3rd, Balmes J, Shusterman D.&lt;br /&gt;
			J Toxicol Environ Health A. 2013;76(10):601-13&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24526601&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Occupational irritant and allergic rhinitis.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
			Shusterman D. &lt;br /&gt;
			Curr Allergy Asthma Rep 2014; 14:425.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mdpi.com/2309-107X/1/1/13&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The nasal nitric oxide response to external acoustic energy: A pilot study of sampling dynamics.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Shusterman D. &lt;br /&gt;
			Sinusitis 2015; 1(1):13-23. 
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27083110&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nonallergic rhinitis: Environmental determinants.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Shusterman D. &lt;br /&gt;
			Immunol All Clin NA 2016; 36(2):379-399.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cognitive function and depression in obstructive lung disease&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20169291&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Onset of depressive  symptoms among adults with asthma: results from a longitudinal observational  cohort.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Katz PP, Morris A, Julian L, Omachi T, Yelin EH, Eisner MD,  Blanc PD.&lt;br /&gt;
			Prim Care Respir J. 2010 Sep;19(3):223-30. &lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20856825&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;COPD and cognitive  impairment: the role of hypoxemia and oxygen therapy.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Thakur N, Blanc PD, Julian LJ, Yelin EH, Katz PP, Sidney S, Iribarren  C, Eisner MD.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon  Dis. 2010 Sep 7;5:263-9.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23332524&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The role of social support in anxiety for persons with COPD&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;
			DiNicola G, Julian L, Gregorich SE, Blanc PD, Katz PP.&lt;br /&gt;
			J Psychosom Res 2013; 74:110-5.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work-related factors in upper limb disorders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21298225&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;1st place, PREMUS best  paper competition: workplace and individual factors in wrist tendinosis among  blue-collar workers--the San Francisco study.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Harris C, Eisen EA, Goldberg R, Krause N, Rempel D.&lt;br /&gt;
			Scand J Work Environ Health. 2011 Mar;37(2):85-98. Epub 2011 Feb 6.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19967325&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Effort-reward imbalance  and one-year change in neck-shoulder and upper extremity pain among call center  computer operators.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Krause N, Burgel B, Rempel D.&lt;br /&gt;
			    Scand J Work Environ Health. 2010 Jan;36(1):42-53. Epub 2009 Dec 7.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20017187&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Follow-up of neck and  shoulder pain among sewing machine operators: The Los Angeles garment study.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Wang PC, Harrison RJ, Yu F, Rempel DM, Ritz BR.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Am J Ind Med. 2010 Apr;53(4):352-60. &lt;/p&gt;
			  
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24932417&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Meta-analysis: association between wrist posture and carpal tunnel syndrome among workers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			You D, Smith AH, Rempel D.&lt;br /&gt;
			Saf Health Work. 2014 Mar;5(1):27-31&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23645610&quot; target=_blank&quot;&gt;
			Personal and workplace psychosocial risk factors for carpal tunnel syndrome: a pooled study cohort.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Harris-Adamson C, Eisen EA, Dale AM, Evanoff B, Hegmann KT, Thiese M, Kapellusch J, Garg A, Burt S, Bao S, Silverstein B, Gerr F, Merlino L, and Rempel D. &lt;br /&gt;
			Occup Environ Med. 2013;70(8):529-37. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24669549&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The impact of posture on wrist tendinosis among blue-collar workers − the San Francisco study.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Harris-Adamson C, Eisen EA, Goldberg R, You D, and Rempel D.  &lt;br /&gt;
			Human Factors. 2014;56(1):143-150. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25563546&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Personal and workplace factors and median nerve function in a pooled study of 2396 US workers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Rempel D, Gerr F, Harris-Adamson C, Hegmann KT, Thiese MS, Eisen EA, Kapellusch J, Garg A, Burt S, Bao S, Silverstein B, Merlino L, Dale AM, Evanoff B.&lt;br /&gt;   
			J Occupational and Environmental Medicine. 2015;57(1):98-104.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25324489&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Biomechanical risk factors for carpal tunnel syndrome:  a pooled study of 2474 workers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Harris-Adamson C, Eisen EA, Kapellusch J, Garg A, Hegmann KT, Thiese MS, Dale AM, Evanoff B, Burt S, Bao S, Silverstein B, Merlino L, Gerr F, Rempel D.&lt;br /&gt;
			Occup Environ Med2015;72(1):33-41.  &lt;/p&gt; 
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25553834&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lateral epicondylitis: New evidence for work relatedness.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
			Descatha A, Dale AM, Silverstein BA, Roquelaure Y, Rempel D.  &lt;br /&gt; 
			Joint Bone Spine 2015; 82(1):5-7. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26552695&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Effectiveness of workplace interventions in the prevention of upper extremity musculoskeletal disorders and symptoms: an update of the evidence.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Van Eerd D, Munhall C, Irvin E, Rempel D, Brewer S, van der Beek AJ,  Dennerlein JT, Tullar J, Skivington K, Pinion C, Amick B.    &lt;br /&gt;
			Occupational and Environmental Medicine 2015 (Epub).  &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27466616&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Biomechanical and psychosocial exposures are independent risk factors for carpal tunnel syndrome: assessment of confounding using causal diagrams. &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Harris-Adamson C, Eisen EA, Neophytou A, Kapellusch J, Garg A, Hegmann KT, Thiese MS, Dale AM, Evanoff B, Bao S, Silverstein B, Gerr F, Burt S, Rempel D.  &lt;br /&gt;
			Occup Environ Med. 2016 Nov;73(11):727-734. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engineering interventions for preventing occupational musculoskeletal disorders&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23024308&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The effects of  periodontal curette handle weight and diameter on arm pain: a four-month  randomized controlled trial.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			Rempel D, Lee DL, Dawson K, Loomer P.&lt;br /&gt;
			J Am Dent Assoc. 2012 Oct;143(10):1105-13.&lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20094939&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Field evaluation of a  modified intervention for overhead drilling.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Rempel D, Star D, Barr A, Blanco MM, Janowitz I.&lt;br /&gt;
			  J Occup Environ Hyg. 2010 Apr;7(4):194-202. &lt;/p&gt;
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17450065&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A randomized controlled  trial evaluating the effects of new task chairs on shoulder and neck pain among  sewing machine operators: the Los Angeles garment study.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
			    Rempel DM, Wang PC, Janowitz I, Harrison RJ, Yu F, Ritz BR.&lt;br /&gt;
			  Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2007 Apr 20;32(9):931-8.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23909815&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Holding a tablet computer with one hand: effect of tablet design features on biomechanics and subjective usability among users with small hands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			Pereira A, Miller T, Huang YM, Odell D, Rempel D.&lt;br /&gt;
			Ergonomics. 2013;56(9):1363-75
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://erg.sagepub.com/content/21/2/15.short&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Effect of handle design on pallet jack operations. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Harris-Adamson C. and Lin J.&lt;br /&gt;
			Ergonomics in Design: The quarterly of Human Factors Applications. 2013;21(2):15-21.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26028955&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The design of gestures for human-computer interaction: Lessons from sign language interpreters. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
			Rempel D, Lee DL, Camilleri M&lt;br /&gt;
			International Journal of Human-Computer Studies 2015; 72(10-11):728-735. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25977321&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A user developed 3D hand gesture set for human-computer interaction.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Pereira A, Wachs JP, Park K, Rempel D.  &lt;br /&gt;  
			Human Factors 2015; 57(4):607-621. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26005290&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A universal rig for supporting large hammer drills: Reduced injury risk and improved productivity.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Rempel D, Barr A.  &lt;br /&gt;
			Safety Science 2015; 78:20-24. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26115682&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;In vivo flexor tendon forces generated during different rehabilitation exercises.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Edsfeldt S, Rempel D, Kursa K, Diao E, Lattanza L. &lt;br /&gt;
			J Hand Surg (Europe) 2015; 40(7):705-10. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26002872&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mind the gap: The effect of keyboard key gap and pitch on typing speed, accuracy, and usability, Part 3.  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Madison H, Pereira A, Korshoj, M, Taylor L, Barr A, Rempel D. &lt;br /&gt;
			Human Factors 2015; 57(7):1188-1194. &lt;br /&gt;
			
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/303695675_Ergonomic_evaluation_of_standard_and_alternative_pallet_jack_handless&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ergonomic evaluation of standard and alternative pallet jack handles. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Harris-Adamson C, Mielke A, Xu X, Lin J.  &lt;br /&gt;
			International Journal of Industrial Ergonomics.  2016; 54:113-119.&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Epidemiology of neurodegenerative diseases&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16162857&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Occupation and parkinsonism in three movement disorders clinics.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Goldman SM, Tanner CM, Olanow CW, Watts RL, Field RD, Langston JW.  
			&lt;br /&gt;Neurology. 65(9):1430-5, 2005.
			&lt;/p&gt; 
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19165397&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Consensus statement:  Parkinson’s disease and the environment.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bronstein J, Carvey P, Chen H, Cory-Slechta D, DiMonte D, Duda J, English P, Goldman S, et. al. &lt;br /&gt; 
			Environmental Health Perspectives. 117(1):117-21, 2009.
			&lt;/p&gt;  
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21269927&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rotenone, paraquat and Parkinson’s disease.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tanner CM, Kamel F, Ross GW, Hoppin JA, Goldman SM, et. al.  
			Environmental Health Perspectives. 119:866-872, 2011. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22083847&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Solvent Exposures and Parkinson Disease Risk in Twins.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Goldman SM, Quinlan PJ, Ross GW, Marras C, Meng C, Bhudhikanok GS, Comyns K, Korell M, Chade AR, Kasten M, Priestley B, Chou KL, Fernandez HH, Cambi F, Langston JW, Tanner CM.  &lt;br /&gt; Annals of Neurology, 71(6),776-784, 2012. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23045187&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Genetic Modification of the Association of Paraquat and Parkinson’s Disease.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Goldman SM, Kamel F, Ross GW, et. al.  
			&lt;br /&gt;Movement Disorders. 27(13):1652-1658, 2012.  
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24050700&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Environmental Toxins and Parkinson’s Disease.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Goldman SM.  
			&lt;br /&gt;Annual Review of Pharmacology and Toxicology. 54:141-64, 2014. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24924672&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The disease intersection of susceptibility and exposure: Chemical exposures and neurodegenerative disease risk.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tanner CM, Goldman SM, Ross GW, Grate SJ.
			&lt;br /&gt;Alzheimer’s and Dementia. 2014 Jun;10(3S):S213-S225. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25461423&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Protective glove use and hygiene habits modify the associations of specific pesticides with Parkinson’s disease.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Furlong M, Tanner CM, Goldman SM, et. al. 
			&lt;br /&gt;Environment International. 2014, Nov 21;75C:144-150. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=24120951&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dietary fat intake, pesticide use, and Parkinson's disease.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Kamel F, Goldman SM, Umbach DM, Chen H, Richardson G, Barber MR, Meng C, Marras C, Korell M, Kasten M, Hoppin JA, Comyns K, Chade A, Blair A, Bhudhikanok GS, Webster Ross G, William Langston J, Sandler DP, Tanner CM. &lt;br /&gt;
			Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2014 Jan; 20(1):82-7. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=26060929&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Head injury, alpha-synuclein Rep1 and Parkinson's Disease: a meta-analytic view of gene-environment interaction. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Goldman SM, Umbach DM, Kamel F, Tanner CM. &lt;br /&gt;
			Eur J Neurol, 2015 Jul;22(7):e75. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcomes in silicosis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Survival following lung transplantation for silicosis and other occupational lung diseases. 
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Singer JP, Chen H, Phelan T, Kukreja J, Golden JA, Blanc PD.
			Occup Med (Lond). 2012 Mar;62(2):134-7. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22383661&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Artificial stone silicosis: Disease resurgence among artificial stone workers. 
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kramer MR, Blanc PD, Fireman E, Amital A Guber A, Rhahman NA, Shitrit D.
			Chest 2012; 142:419-24 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26070814&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Outbreak of autoimmune disease in silicosis linked to artificial stone.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Shtraichman O, Blanc PD, Ollech JE, Fridel L, Fuks L, Fireman E, Kramer MR 
			Occup Med (London) 2015;65:444-50. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/?term=%E2%80%9CAcute%E2%80%9D+Silicosis+in+the+1930+Johannesburg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Acute” Silicosis in the 1930 Johannesburg International Silicosis Conference and in its aftermath:  Controversies over a distinct entity later recognized as silicoproteinosis. 
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Blanc PD.
			Am J Ind Med  2015; 2015;58 (Suppl 1):39-47. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26007670&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Prospective risk of rheumatologic disease associated with occupational exposure in a cohort of male construction workers. 
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Blanc PD, Järvholm B, Torén K. 
			Am J Med  2015; 128:1094-1101. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			 &lt;/blockquote&gt;
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribution of occupational and environmental factors to COPD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Further exploration of the links between occupational exposure and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. 
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Blanc PD, Eisner MD, Earnest G, Trupin L, Balmes JR, Yelin EH, Gregorich SE, Katz PP.
			&lt;br /&gt;J Occup Environ Med. 2009 Jul;51(7):804-10. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease among residents of an historically industrialised area. 
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Darby AC, Waterhouse JC, Stevens V, Billings CG, Billings CG, Burton CM, Young C, Wight J, Blanc PD, Fishwick D. 
			&lt;br /&gt;Thorax. 2012 Oct;67(10):901-7. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24983136&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secondhand Tobacco Smoke and COPD Risk in Smokers: A COPDGene Study Cohort Subgroup Analysis.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Koeverden Iv, Blanc PD, Bowler RP, Arjomandi M.  COPD. 2015; 2(2):182-9. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25822819&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Investigation of hydrogen sulfide exposure and lung function, asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease in a geothermal area of New Zealand.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Bates MN, Crane J, Balmes JR, Garrett N.&lt;br /&gt;
			PLoS One. 2015 Mar 30;10(3):e0122062. 
			
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27725189&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;High risks of lung disease associated with early-life and moderate lifetime arsenic exposure in northern Chile.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Steinmaus C, Ferreccio C, Acevedo J, Balmes JR, Liaw J, Troncoso P, Dauphiné DC, Nardone A, Smith AH.&lt;br /&gt;
			Toxicol Appl Pharmacol. 2016 Oct 8;313:10-15. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27318255&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Differential respiratory health effects from the 2008 northern California wildfires: A spatiotemporal approach.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Reid CE, Jerrett M, Tager IB, Petersen ML, Mann JK, Balmes JR.&lt;br /&gt;
			Environ Res. 2016 Oct;150:227-35.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Physiological biomarkers of early obstructive lung disease&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25398189&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Exposure to household air pollution from wood combustion and association with respiratory symptoms and lung function in nonsmoking women: results from the RESPIRE trial, Guatemala.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Pope D, Diaz E, Smith-Sivertsen T, Lie RT, Bakke P, Balmes JR, Smith KR, Bruce NG.&lt;br /&gt;
			Environ Health Perspect. 2015 Apr;123(4):285-92. &lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			
			
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cardiopulmonary health effects of exposure to ozone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26681363&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Long-Term Ozone Exposure Increases the Risk of Developing the Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Ware LB, Zhao Z, Koyama T, May AK, Matthay MA, Lurmann FW, Balmes JR, Calfee CS.&lt;br /&gt;
			Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2016 May 15;193(10):1143-50.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27533426&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The last Summer Olympics? Climate change, health, and work outdoors.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Smith KR, Woodward A, Lemke B, Otto M, Chang CJ, Mance AA, Balmes J, Kjellstrom T.
			Lancet. 2016 Aug 13;388(10045):642-4. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18087591&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Effects of chronic and acute ozone exposure on lipid peroxidation and antioxidant capacity in healthy young adults.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Chen C, Arjomandi M, Balmes J, Tager I, Holland N.  
			&lt;br /&gt;Environ Health Perspect. 2007;115(12):1732-7.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25451016&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ozone inhalation leads to a dose-dependent increase of cytogenetic damage in human lymphocytes.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Holland N, Davé V, Venkat S, Wong H, Donde A, Balmes JR, Arjomandi M.    Environ &lt;br /&gt;Mol Mutagen. 2015; 56(4):378-87. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25862833&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Exposure to medium and high ambient levels of ozone causes adverse systemic inflammatory and cardiac autonomic effects.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Arjomandi M, Wong H, Donde A, Frelinger J, Dalton S, Ching W, Power K, Balmes JR.    
			&lt;br /&gt;Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2015; 308(12):H1499-509. 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26035830&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Inflammatory and repair pathways induced in human bronchoalveolar lavage cells with ozone inhalation.
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Leroy P, Tham A, Wong H, Tenney R, Chen C, Stiner R, Balmes JR, Paquet AC, Arjomandi M.  
			&lt;br /&gt;PLoS One. 2015 Jun 2;10(6):e0127283.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Childhood and reproductive environmental health&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26613694&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Children’s environmental health: Beyond national boundaries
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Miller MD, Marty MA, Landrigan PJ. 
			&lt;br /&gt;Pediatric Clinics of North America. 2016 Feb;63(1):149-65.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26485730&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thyroid hormones and moderate exposure to perchlorate during pregnancy in women in Southern California. 
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steinmaus C, Pearl M, Kharrazi M, Blount BC, Miller MD, Pearce EN, Valentin-Blasini L, DeLorenze G, Hoofnagle AN, Liaw J 
			&lt;br /&gt;Environ Health Perspect. 2015 Oct 20 
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26334434&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Children’s cancer and environmental exposures: Professional attitudes and practices. 
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Zachek  CM, Miller MD, Hsu C, Schiffman JD, Sallen S, Metayer C, Dahl GV.  
			&lt;br /&gt;J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2015 Oct;37(7):491-7.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26253210&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Arsenic and rice: Translating research to address health care providers’ needs. 
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lai PY, Cottingham KL, Steinmaus C, Karagas MR, Miller MD. 
			&lt;br /&gt;J Pediatr. 2015 Oct;167(4):797-803.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			 
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22405527&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Toxic environmental chemicals: The role of reproductive health professionals in preventing harmful exposures
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sutton P, Woodruff TJ, Perron J, Stotland N, Conroy JA, Miller MD, Giudice LC. 
			&lt;br /&gt;Am J Obs Gyn March 2012.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26634937&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			Decreased lung function in 7-year-old children with early-life organophosphate exposure.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Raanan R, Balmes JR, Harley KG, Gunier RB, Magzamen S, Bradman A, Eskenazi B.&lt;br /&gt;
			Thorax. 2016 Feb;71(2):148-53. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25369257&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Early-life exposure to organophosphate pesticides and pediatric respiratory symptoms in the CHAMACOS cohort.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Raanan R, Harley KG, Balmes JR, Bradman A, Lipsett M, Eskenazi B.&lt;br /&gt;
			Environ Health Perspect. 2015 Feb;123(2):179-85. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25305053&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Genetic modification of the effect of maternal household air pollution exposure on birth weight in Guatemalan newborns.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Thompson LM, Yousefi P, Peñaloza R, Balmes J, Holland N.&lt;br /&gt;
			Reprod Toxicol. 2014 Dec;50:19-26. &lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secondhand and Thirdhand Cigarette Smoke Exposure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;blockquote&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19448573&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pulmonary function abnormalities in never-smoking flight attendants exposed to secondhand tobacco smoke in the aircraft cabin.&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Arjomandi M, Haight T, Redberg R, Gold WM.  
			&lt;br /&gt;J Occup Environ Med. 2009 Jun;51(6):639-46.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22493689&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reduced exercise tolerance and pulmonary capillary recruitment with remote secondhand smoke exposure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Arjomandi M, Haight T, Sadeghi N, Redberg R, Gold WM.  
			&lt;br /&gt;PLoS One. 2012;7(4):e34393.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26753171&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Impairment of Endothelial Function by Little Cigar Secondhand Smoke&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			Liu J, Wang X, Narayan S, Glantz SA, Schick SF, Springer ML.&lt;br /&gt;
			Tob Regul Sci. 2016 Jan 1;2(1):56-63.
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27255386&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;From the Cover: Thirdhand Cigarette Smoke Causes Stress-Induced Mitochondrial Hyperfusion and Alters the Transcriptional Profile of Stem Cells&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
			Bahl V, Johnson K, Phandthong R, Zahedi A, Schick SF, Talbot P.&lt;br /&gt;
			Toxicol Sci. 2016 Sep;153(1):55-69. doi: 10.1093/toxsci/kfw102.
			
			&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;/blockquote&gt;
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
33index
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			&lt;h3&gt;UC Occupational &amp; Environmental Medicine Links
			&lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coeh.berkeley.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Center for Occupational and Environmental Health &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Center for Occupational and Environmental Health (COEH) and its sister centers at Los Angeles and Irvine serve government, industry, schools, health professionals, and the general public through programs and partnerships designed to deepen understanding of occupational and environmental hazards and to prevent disease, fatalities, and injuries.
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.occupationalhealthprogram.ucsf.edu/index.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UCSF Occupational Health Program &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Occupational Health Program integrates medical surveillance, risk assessment, clinical occupational health services, and disability management to improve the occupational health and safety of the UCSF community.
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ucsfhealth.org/clinics/occupational_and_environmental_medicine/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;UCSF Occupational and Environmental Medicine Clinic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Occupational and Environmental Medicine Clinic provides consultation for patients and their families with injuries, illnesses, exposures or health concerns related to their workplace, community or home. Our doctors provide diagnosis and treatment of work-related injury and illness under workers' compensation, and can perform in-depth expert consultation for disability and return-to-work. We are familiar with the latest studies on chemical exposure and health effects, and can arrange for workplace visits and testing to make recommendations about reducing or eliminating hazards.
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cme.ucsf.edu/cme/CourseDetail.aspx?coursenumber=MDM13N01&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Occupational and Environmental Factors in Neurological Disease and Occupational and Environmental Medicine Update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The University of California San Francisco is hosting a special conference, “Occupational and Environmental Factors in Neurological Disease” to take place on Thursday November 1, 2012.  The special Conference will be followed by the “Occupational and Environmental Medicine Update” on November 2-3 with a day and a half of our Division’s regular CME course updating a variety of topics in occupational and environmental medicine. 
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/household-hazards&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Household Hazards&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Dr. Paul Blanc writes a blog focusing on occupational and environmental health issues hosted on Psychology Today.
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/tutorials.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OEM Tutorials &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A series of interactive case studies based upon the clinical experiences of faculty and trainees at the Divsion of OEM at UCSF.  Partially supported by an instructional media grant from the UCSF Library.
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://ergo.berkeley.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ergonomics Program&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The Ergonomics Program is affiliated with the Center for Occupational and Environmental Health, a University of California umbrella organization that links faculty and research programs with research interest in occupational health from the Berkeley, Davis and San Francisco campuses. The Program's laboratory is located at U.C. Berkeley's Richmond Field Station, a research station administered by the College of Engineering.
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
			
			
			
			
			&lt;h3&gt;Occupational Safety Links &lt;/h3&gt;
			&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.calpoison.org/home.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;California Poison Control (CPCS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The California Poison Control provides immediate, free and expert treatment advice and referral over the telephone in case of exposure to poisonous or toxic substances.
			&lt;/li&gt;
			
			&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cpwr.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Center to Protect Workers' Rights (CPWR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Center to Protect Workers' Rights is affiliated with the Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL-CIO. It focuses on construction and ergonomics issues. Site includes hazard alerts in English and Spanish, press releases, an ergonomics checklist, publication information, research papers, and more. Also see the separate listing for CPWR's Electronic Library below. 
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elcosh.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CPWR—Electronic Library of Construction Safety and Health (eLCOSH)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Center to Protect Workers’ Rights has gathered this extensive library of material on construction safety and health. Workers, contractors, researchers, and others can download information from many sources in English, Spanish, and other languages. Funding for eLCOSH is provided by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH). Materials include pocket cards, brochures, manuals, newsletters, research reports, directories, training curricula, data sets, bibliographies, and regulations. Has LOHP's Tailgate Training materials online. (These materials are also available in print and online through LOHP's Publications page.) 
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cpwrconstructionsolutions.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Construction Solutions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The Construction Solutions database is a free online database for owners, contractors and workers that highlights hazards in construction work, as well as control or reduce those hazards. This database allows workers and contractors to identify hazards associated with construction tasks, and obtain options for controlling those hazards. An interactive website, Construction Solutions allows users to submit: reviews of existing solutions, suggestions for additional reviews or requests to assist us in continued development activity.
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.woema.org/index.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Western Occupational &amp; Environmental Medical Association (WOEMA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; WOEMA is a regional component of the American College of Occupational and Environmental Medicine (ACOEM), and is dedicated to high quality medical care and ethical principles governing the practice of occupational medicine.
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdph.ca.gov/programs/ohb/Pages/default.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Occupational Health Branch (OHB)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			The Occupational Health Branch is a program in the California Department of Public Health devoted to improving worker health and safety through prevention activities.  OHB works to prevent injury and illness on the job before they happen
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ehib.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Environmental Health Investigations Branch (EHIB)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			EHIB works to optimize the health of the people in California by studying how the environment affects health and by educating and informing the public. The environment is the world around us, it is where we live, work and play. We come into contact with the environment through the air we breathe, the food we eat, and the water we drink.
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acoem.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;American College of Occupational and Environmental Medicine (ACOEM)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
			The American College of Occupational and Environmental Medicine (ACOEM) represents more than 4,500 physicians and other health care professionals specializing in the field of occupational and environmental medicine (OEM).
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://aoec.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Association of Occupational and Environmental Clinics (AOEC)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Established in 1987 the Association of Occupational and Environmental Clinics, a non-profit organization, is committed to improving the practice of occupational and environmental health through information sharing and collaborative research.
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dir.ca.gov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;California Department of Industrial Relations (DIR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			The Department of Industrial Relations was established to improve working conditions for California's wage earners, and to advance opportunities for profitable employment in California.
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
			&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cdc.gov/niosh/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
			Providing National and World Leadership to Prevent Workplace Illnesses and Injuries.
			
			
			&lt;/li&gt;
			
			&lt;/ul&gt;
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
	<node>
		<Fname>
34tutorials
		</Fname>
        <location>1736</location>
		<FileBody>
			
			
			                       
			
			&lt;p class=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;A series of interactive case studies based upon the clinical experiences of faculty and trainees at the Divsion of OEM at UCSF.  Partially supported by an instructional media grant from the UCSF Library.&lt;/p&gt;
			  
			&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/DCM/player.html&quot;&gt;Headaches and mucous membrane irritation in a furniture refinisher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/Hazmat/quiz.html&quot;&gt;Fatality in a hazardous materials incident&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/Hazmat-Rev/quiz_html5.html&quot;&gt;Fatality in a hazardous...(Mobile version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
				    
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/2np/quiz.html&quot;&gt;Two men sick after working in an underground vault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/2np-Rev/quiz_html5.html&quot;&gt;Two men sick...(Mobile version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/n-hexane/quiz.html&quot;&gt; A mechanic with numbness and tingling of the extremities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/n-hexane-Rev/quiz_html5.html&quot;&gt; A mechanic with numbness...(Mobile version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/Isocyanate/quiz.html&quot;&gt; Nocturnal cough in an auto body painter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/Isocyanate-Rev/quiz_html5.html&quot;&gt; Nocturnal cough...(Mobile version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/Dyspnea/quiz.html&quot;&gt; Fatigue and shortness-of-breath in a truck driver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/Dyspnea-Rev/quiz_html5.html&quot;&gt; Fatigue...(Mobile version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/Recycling/quiz.html&quot;&gt; Shortness-of-breath in a recycling facility employee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/Recycling-Rev/quiz_html5.html&quot;&gt; Shortness-of-breath...(Mobile version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/Fatigue/quiz.html&quot;&gt; Episodic fever, chills and cough in a 33 year-old software developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ocf.berkeley.edu/~dshuster/Fatigue-Rev/quiz_html5.html&quot;&gt; Episodic fever...(Mobile version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
			
			&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
			
			
		</FileBody>
	</node>
</nodes>